<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Peculiar Monster</title><link>https://peculiar.monster/</link><description>Recent content on Peculiar Monster</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>GigaMeow</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 11:18:02 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://peculiar.monster/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Trying to Post Images</title><link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/image-posting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 11:18:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/image-posting/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m trying to figure out how to manage images; I don&amp;rsquo;t really want to do &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/content-management/page-bundles/">page bundles&lt;/a>&amp;hellip;but I guess I am for now. Meh.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Code, Why Are You Like This?</title><link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/code-why-are-you-like-this/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 11:35:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/code-why-are-you-like-this/</guid><description>&lt;p>And of course, no sooner than I finished my previous post and decided to deploy the site than I ran into a bunch of problems, some bigger than others.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hello World</title><link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 20:06:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/hello-world/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hello world!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While this is a new site, I am not new to blogging. I&amp;rsquo;ve been blogging one way or another since 1999, give or take. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a lot of different sites over the years&amp;ndash;from Diaryland to Greymatter to Movable Type to LiveJournal to WordPress and now I&amp;rsquo;m using &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io">Hugo&lt;/a> because, to be quite honest, I am unhappy with the direction WordPress has taken their product&amp;ndash;they seem to assume that everyone wants to sell something and too often what&amp;rsquo;s for sale is a piece of someone&amp;rsquo;s soul.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have no desire to make this site generate any sort of regular source of income or to leverage it into something bigger than what it is. I&amp;rsquo;m not looking for visibility or followers or to become any sort of influencer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m looking for a place to document my life and how I&amp;rsquo;m living it.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Blogroll</title><link>https://peculiar.monster/blogroll/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 17:09:43 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://peculiar.monster/blogroll/</guid><description>I used to read so many blogs and other sources of information. Sadly, fewer and fewer folks are blogging on their own sites and instead opt for places like Twitter or Substack, the latter often behind a paywall (And yet, nearly all of the newsletters I&amp;rsquo;m going to recommend are on Substack; probably because Substack positions itself as a content provider and not a way to get people into your sales funnel).</description></item><item><title>About Gigameow</title><link>https://peculiar.monster/about/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 07:07:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://peculiar.monster/about/</guid><description>Hello! I am:
a cyborgified human being1 femme non-binary my pronouns are she/they married to a wonderful man since 2006, but we&amp;rsquo;ve been partners since 1998 chronically ill with a whole bunch of fascinating things2 owned by two cats, Miles and Ivan (yes, nominative determinism is a thing) a voracious reader of speculative fiction and possessed of many opinions including that George R.R. Martin can fuck off into the sun3 loser of not one, but two Hugo Awards a knitter, crocheter, and spinner a failed poet a watercolor painter and sticker collector in recovery from a corporate America and toxic productivity a web developer&amp;ndash;mostly JavaScript and Vue.</description></item></channel></rss>