<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title>knitting - Tag - Peculiar Monster</title><link>https://peculiar.monster/tags/knitting/</link><description>knitting - Tag - Peculiar Monster</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>hello@peculiar.monster (gigameow)</managingEditor><webMaster>hello@peculiar.monster (gigameow)</webMaster><copyright>copyright 2022</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 11:18:02 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://peculiar.monster/tags/knitting/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Trying to Post Images</title><link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/image-posting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 11:18:02 -0400</pubDate><author>gigameow</author><guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/image-posting/</guid><description><![CDATA[<p>I&rsquo;m trying to figure out how to manage images; I don&rsquo;t really want to do <a href="https://gohugo.io/content-management/page-bundles/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">page bundles</a>&hellip;but I guess I am for now. Meh.</p>
<p>Annnnd, of course, I can&rsquo;t get any of the theme&rsquo;s built-in image shortcodes to actually <em>respect</em> my settings&ndash;do I want my images linked? No, no I do not. And why the FUCK is it not rendering the CSS that at least hides my link formatting? I have it in the right order, it&rsquo;s just straight-up <em>ignoring</em> me. I&rsquo;m starting to think I need to find another, simpler theme to work with. This one is awfully finicky and NOT GOOD at respecting my choices. Which is why I wanted to get away from the WordPress ecosystem in the first place: to have better choices.</p>
<p>Anyhow. Enjoy this image of my African violet blooming&ndash;I&rsquo;ve never had one bloom before, and I&rsquo;ve even managed to keep it alive for over a year. That&rsquo;s a victory, for sure. The second image is of my current knitting project, <a href="https://www.ravelry.com/patterns/library/mutual-admiration-society" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreffer">Mutual Admiration Society</a> (Rav link, sorry), which I bought as a kit eons ago. It uses a technique new to me, mosaic knitting, which is slipping stitches on every row with two alternating colors. It looks a lot harder than it actually is. The gray speckled yarn is Miss Babs&rsquo;s Yowza and it is incredible to work with&ndash;I would love to make a sweater with this stuff, it&rsquo;s so round and bouncy and nice to work with.</p>
<p>

</p>
<p>

</p>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->]]></description></item></channel></rss>