<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>langston hughes on Peculiar Monster</title><link>https://peculiar.monster/tags/langston-hughes/</link><description>Recent content in langston hughes on Peculiar Monster</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>GigaMeow</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 16:48:39 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://peculiar.monster/tags/langston-hughes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The land that never has been yet—</title><link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/the-land-that-never-has-been-yet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 16:48:39 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/the-land-that-never-has-been-yet/</guid><description>&lt;p>Langston Hughes said it better than I can, especially for this 4th of July, one where we&amp;rsquo;re reeling from the endgame of a culture war that started before I was born.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;h1 id="let-america-be-america-again">Let America Be America Again&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Let America be America again.&lt;br>
Let it be the dream it used to be.&lt;br>
Let it be the pioneer on the plain&lt;br>
Seeking a home where he himself is free.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(America never was America to me.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let America be the dream the dreamers dreamed—&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let it be that great strong land of love&lt;br>
Where never kings connive nor tyrants scheme&lt;br>
That any man be crushed by one above.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(It never was America to me.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>O, let my land be a land where Liberty&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Is crowned with no false patriotic wreath,&lt;br>
But opportunity is real, and life is free,&lt;br>
Equality is in the air we breathe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(There’s never been equality for me,&lt;br>
Nor freedom in this “homeland of the free.”)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Say, who are you that mumbles in the dark?&lt;/em>&lt;br>
&lt;em>And who are you that draws your veil across the stars?&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am the poor white, fooled and pushed apart,&lt;br>
I am the Negro bearing slavery’s scars.&lt;br>
I am the red man driven from the land,&lt;br>
I am the immigrant clutching the hope I seek—&lt;br>
And finding only the same old stupid plan&lt;br>
Of dog eat dog, of mighty crush the weak.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am the young man, full of strength and hope,&lt;br>
Tangled in that ancient endless chain&lt;br>
Of profit, power, gain, of grab the land!&lt;br>
Of grab the gold! Of grab the ways of satisfying need!&lt;br>
Of work the men! Of take the pay!&lt;br>
Of owning everything for one’s own greed!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am the farmer, bondsman to the soil.&lt;br>
I am the worker sold to the machine.&lt;br>
I am the Negro, servant to you all.&lt;br>
I am the people, humble, hungry, mean—&lt;br>
Hungry yet today despite the dream.&lt;br>
Beaten yet today—O, Pioneers!&lt;br>
I am the man who never got ahead,&lt;br>
The poorest worker bartered through the years.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yet I’m the one who dreamt our basic dream&lt;br>
In the Old World while still a serf of kings,&lt;br>
Who dreamt a dream so strong, so brave, so true,&lt;br>
That even yet its mighty daring sings&lt;br>
In every brick and stone, in every furrow turned&lt;br>
That’s made America the land it has become.&lt;br>
O, I’m the man who sailed those early seas&lt;br>
In search of what I meant to be my home—&lt;br>
For I’m the one who left dark Ireland’s shore,&lt;br>
And Poland’s plain, and England’s grassy lea,&lt;br>
And torn from Black Africa’s strand I came&lt;br>
To build a “homeland of the free.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The free?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Who said the free? Not me?&lt;br>
Surely not me? The millions on relief today?&lt;br>
The millions shot down when we strike?&lt;br>
The millions who have nothing for our pay?&lt;br>
For all the dreams we’ve dreamed&lt;br>
And all the songs we’ve sung&lt;br>
And all the hopes we’ve held&lt;br>
And all the flags we’ve hung,&lt;br>
The millions who have nothing for our pay—&lt;br>
Except the dream that’s almost dead today.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>O, let America be America again—&lt;br>
The land that never has been yet—&lt;br>
And yet must be—the land where &lt;em>every&lt;/em> man is free.&lt;br>
The land that’s mine—the poor man’s, Indian’s, Negro’s, ME—&lt;br>
Who made America,&lt;br>
Whose sweat and blood, whose faith and pain,&lt;br>
Whose hand at the foundry, whose plow in the rain,&lt;br>
Must bring back our mighty dream again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sure, call me any ugly name you choose—&lt;br>
The steel of freedom does not stain.&lt;br>
From those who live like leeches on the people’s lives,&lt;br>
We must take back our land again,&lt;br>
America!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>O, yes,&lt;br>
I say it plain,&lt;br>
America never was America to me,&lt;br>
And yet I swear this oath—&lt;br>
America will be!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Out of the rack and ruin of our gangster death,&lt;br>
The rape and rot of graft, and stealth, and lies,&lt;br>
We, the people, must redeem&lt;br>
The land, the mines, the plants, the rivers.&lt;br>
The mountains and the endless plain—&lt;br>
All, all the stretch of these great green states—&lt;br>
And make America again!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ndash;&lt;em>Langston Hughes&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item></channel></rss>