<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>sff on Peculiar Monster</title><link>https://peculiar.monster/tags/sff/</link><description>Recent content in sff on Peculiar Monster</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>GigaMeow</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 22:15:34 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://peculiar.monster/tags/sff/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Coding and Thinking</title><link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/coding-and-thinking/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 22:15:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/coding-and-thinking/</guid><description>&lt;p>Did you know that I have not one, but two kanban boards? One for getting this site set up as I want it to be, and another for mothballing my old site.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They both have a LOT of things on them. It&amp;rsquo;s gonna be a lot of work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But this evening, I knocked out a fair number of backend things I wanted to fix on this site, primarily with the CSS. I figured out what all the different files were doing, removed the parts that were irrelevant (goodbye stupid jquery menu on mobile), and did my various imports in a way that made sense for me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also replaced a few things with links to CDNs instead of hosting the entire content here&amp;ndash;that allows me to keep up to date with the most current version of things but it does add a vulnerability in case those CDNs go down. They&amp;rsquo;re mostly for things like some of the icons and the CSS frameword the original author chose to use. If the CDNs do go down, things will degrade gracefully until they come back up again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On a completely different topic:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Folks on Twitter have been so kind and I wrote yesterday about the &lt;a href="https://peculiar.monster/posts/f-stands-for-fungible">reasons I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen to distance myself from fandom&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wanted to give an example of the sort of lifting of phrasing/ideas in such a way that it&amp;rsquo;s clear that my work was the inspiration&amp;ndash;I ran across this just last night:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wrote on August 1, 2020:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Martin made the decision to first mention her unprecedented accomplishment of winning the Best Novel three years in a row–-no one else of any race or gender has ever accomplished a Best Novel hat trick–-and then attempt to undermine it&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And in the the essay I ran across yesterday, that author wrote:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Martin has also been criticized for disrespecting the award winners, mispronouncing names and undercutting accomplishments like N. K. Jemisin’s “hat trick” of three Hugo awards for best novel in as many years,&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s not a word for word lifting, but as far as I know, I am the person who first referred to Jemisin&amp;rsquo;s historic achievement as a &amp;ldquo;hat trick,&amp;rdquo; and I immedately followed it with Martin&amp;rsquo;s attempt to undermine it. (I included the content of his undermining attempt, too.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this piece, the author uses undercut before mentioning Jemisin&amp;rsquo;s achievement. I know that undercut &lt;strong>isn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/strong> the same word, but it can be used interchangeably with undermine in this context.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not linking the essay in question because I don&amp;rsquo;t want to stir up trouble, but this is the sort of low-grade theft I&amp;rsquo;ve dealt with for the last decade. My essays are good enough to read and gain inspiration from, but not good enough to cite.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll also note that apart my words, the author did an excellent job both sourcing and citing their sources.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please think about why that may be.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the aftermath of my post, I was accused of posting for clout, for hating George, for using indecent language, for being jealous, fo being all sorts of things I just wasn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You know why I posted it? I was angry. I was angry that someone with the stature of George R.R. Martin couldn&amp;rsquo;t be bothered to take the time to learn how to say people&amp;rsquo;s names, but took the time to figure out which hat he was going to wear for which segment and which action figures he was going to put on display. I was angry that he made the entire ceremony about how good the past was, with no acknowledgement that the past SUCKED for a lot of people and still SUCKS for them STILL. I was angry on behalf of my friends and colleagues who had turned on the ceremony excited to see their works celebrated and who instead THAT.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yeah, I swore. And yeah, I used a metaphor involving the sun. And yeeting people into it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And I happened to be the first person to post any sort of response online. Which is the only reason it got the audience that it did.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, imagine, how I felt afterwards, being accused of everything I wasn&amp;rsquo;t and also knowing that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t defend myself. It was like all those writing workshops all over again: I had to sit and take the abuse in silence. And I&amp;rsquo;ve been taking the abuse in (relative) silence for nearly two years now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s just been a lot. And I&amp;rsquo;m probably going to be writing a lot about my trauma here&amp;ndash;not just with regards to fandom, but also about my childhood.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ve been forewarned.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>F Stands for Fungible</title><link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/f-stands-for-fungible/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 16:55:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/f-stands-for-fungible/</guid><description>&lt;p>I started the process of mothballing my old site last night.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was really hard to go through nearly 700 posts and unpublish them, leaving only the ones I&amp;rsquo;m planning on archiving on a static site.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Really, really hard. Also hard was seeing people respond on Twitter to my statement a few days ago that I was shutting the site down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been, personally, a terrible few years. I&amp;rsquo;ve lost my health, my career, and now I&amp;rsquo;m losing the vast majority of my social network. I am &lt;strong>gutted&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The ongoing harassment, silencing, and other kinds of abuse I&amp;rsquo;ve had to deal with over the nearly 10 years I&amp;rsquo;ve been publishing there&amp;ndash;it&amp;rsquo;s just too much. I think that if I hadn&amp;rsquo;t felt so alone during last year&amp;rsquo;s Hugo season and if people with larger platforms on social media had done &lt;strong>something&lt;/strong> to defend me instead of choosing to let me be the tank for people&amp;rsquo;s dissatisfaction with the Hugo ballot&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because that was a &lt;strong>choice&lt;/strong>. Let&amp;rsquo;s not pretend that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t. A lot of people knew how distressed I was by the bad faith arguments and the intimations that if I were a decent person, I&amp;rsquo;d have refused the nomination and they chose to say and do nothing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then when I was brigaded by a bunch of leftier-than-thou jackasses after the Hugos&amp;ndash;again, no support. The fiction finalists who received abuse did get a lot of support, but when I posted in the finalist Slack that I was also being abused and the only other person who responded was another fan, well. That showed me who the SFF community finds importand and who they don&amp;rsquo;t. Shortly after, I quietly peaced out of the Slack since I no longer felt welcome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I often joke that F doesn&amp;rsquo;t stand for fan, it stands for fungible.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>fungible&lt;/strong>: being something (such as money or a commodity) of such a nature that one part or quantity may be replaced by another equal part or quantity in paying a debt or settling an account&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That is, fans like myself are seen by many pro writers and SMOFs as interchangeable cogs in the SFF community. And since we are fungible, when someone&amp;rsquo;s pushed aside or leaves, well, it&amp;rsquo;s not a big deal. Someone else will certainly come along. And I am definitely feeling disposable. Surely, there will come along someone else to fill my particular niche in the SFF community. I wish them luck, because they&amp;rsquo;re going to need it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve talked a little bit about what I&amp;rsquo;ve had to deal with over the last ten years, let me make it explicit:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>professional writers I thought were friends not only expressing relief that my essay didn&amp;rsquo;t win a Hugo, but the fact that it was nominated was a disgrace and saying so in a place where I could not only see it, but interact with it&amp;ndash;and their silence when I expressed my disappointment that they hadn&amp;rsquo;t bothered to hide it from me
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the comments on said post, some of which called my nomination the worst thing ever to happen to the Hugos, &lt;strong>worse&lt;/strong> than that time Harlan Ellison grabbed Connie Willis&amp;rsquo;s breast at the Hugo Awards Ceremony (there is video, you can look it up)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>aforementioned brigading by a bunch of leftier-than-thou jackasses on Twitter
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the ringleaders have also made photoshopped memes of a post I deleted which they think is &lt;strong>hilarious&lt;/strong> (it&amp;rsquo;s not)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>one of them also published a &amp;ldquo;poem&amp;rdquo; which was &amp;ldquo;inspired&amp;rdquo; by my deleted tweet and which also included the image and the tweet&amp;rsquo;s text&lt;/li>
&lt;li>their creation of a &amp;ldquo;movement&amp;rdquo; in SFF that they can&amp;rsquo;t even define cogently which appears to have been created, in part, as a way to direct harassment towards me by getting the attention of professional writers with a significant platform&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ongoing defense of the subject of my essay, which is just weird because he&amp;rsquo;s a cis het white man with a swimming pool full of money: presumably everything they hate about capitalism and the power structures it sustains&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>having my work appropriated by professional non-fiction writers and not credited and when they were asked to credit me, made pathetic excuses&lt;/li>
&lt;li>endless accusations of whining, of jealousy, or of just wanting more traffic&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&amp;ldquo;friendly advice&amp;rdquo; to be less blunt, to be nicer, to be quiet&lt;/li>
&lt;li>abusive comments calling me names, making fun of my appearance, telling me to die and/or kill myself&lt;/li>
&lt;li>doxxed 3 times in 2 years by trolls, Worldcon, and SFWA&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Legitimate criticism and engaging with my arguments? I have no problem with that. It&amp;rsquo;s when all this other stuff happens and happens because I&amp;rsquo;m saying things that people don&amp;rsquo;t like or don&amp;rsquo;t want to hear or because I don&amp;rsquo;t look the way they think I should (pray tell, how &lt;strong>should&lt;/strong> I look?).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And it&amp;rsquo;s been ongoing for nearly 10 years and for the most part, the attacks are &lt;strong>coming from inside the house&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Is it any wonder that I feel like I need a little space to re-grow and to find my voice again?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean I&amp;rsquo;m not sad about walking away: I am. I know that there are many people that I will lose touch with, since I won&amp;rsquo;t be interacting with them on Twitter or seeing them at conventions. I know that when I do start attending conventions again, I won&amp;rsquo;t be asked to be on programming anymore&amp;ndash;and I love being on panels and I&amp;rsquo;ve been told that I&amp;rsquo;m good at being on panels.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Perhaps, eventually, I&amp;rsquo;ll feel comfortable shedding this pseudonym. For now, though, it&amp;rsquo;s exactly what I need.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Current Feelings Towards SFF Fandom</title><link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/sff-feelings-mood/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 13:25:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/sff-feelings-mood/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="acnh-big-mood.png" alt="An Animal Crossing New Horizons character sitting in a cheap lawn chair in the evening with a tray table full of empty alcohol bottles next to them. In front of them is a burning oil barrel, two bags of trash, a can of gasoline, and a fire extinguisher. The character is wearing a red hat and a blue shirt that has a white cat on it shooting laser beam out of its eyes. The character&amp;rsquo;s eyes are half-closed, their mouth is open in dismay, and there are two bubble floating near their head. It&amp;rsquo;s evening.">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a fairly accurate description of how I&amp;rsquo;m currently feeling about SFF fandom. Burn it all down, my children.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Random Thoughts (June 9)</title><link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/random-thoughts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 09:52:04 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/random-thoughts/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oof. I went in for my monthly-ish paracentesis yesterday morning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you don&amp;rsquo;t know what this is, here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paracentesis">a handy explainer from Wikipedia&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First of all, I was up entirely too early for my own good. But it did mean I was able to take my meds and eat breakfast before having to leave for the hospital, so that&amp;rsquo;s something, yes?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Normally, it&amp;rsquo;s not too bad, but the doctor doing them yesterday was a resident and while she was very nice and perfectly competent, she was also still a &lt;em>resident&lt;/em>, which means that she wasn&amp;rsquo;t as skilled as some of the doctors who have been there for years. And I&amp;rsquo;m a bit of a tough case&amp;ndash;I get tapped on my left side, not the right, and I&amp;rsquo;m not a high volume person anymore (thank God&amp;ndash;that&amp;rsquo;s 5L or more).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I got home, I took my pain meds and went directly to bed. I ended up spending most of the day in bed, which meant I didn&amp;rsquo;t get good sleep last night&amp;ndash;which means I was up at 4:30 am this morning for a few hours (I was able to see the day restart on Animal Crossing, which I&amp;rsquo;d never done before, so yay?) and then was able to get back to sleep for a couple of hours and then I was up for the day. And I&amp;rsquo;m still in a bit of pain. Boo.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My code editor&amp;ndash;Atom&amp;ndash;is being sunset at the end of the year, so I&amp;rsquo;m looking for alternatives. I&amp;rsquo;m leaning towards Sublime Text and Sublime Merge over VSCode, mainly because I feel like VSCode is bloated as all get out. It makes me cranky, though, because I &lt;em>finally&lt;/em> got a good workflow going in Atom and managed to learn a bunch of keyboard shortcuts and now I&amp;rsquo;m going to have to learn different ones. Meh.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Still haven&amp;rsquo;t had a chance to rework the colors here, but maybe this weekend? There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of weirdness in the CSS&amp;ndash;like the theme&amp;rsquo;s author made a &lt;em>separate&lt;/em> CSS file for each partial template and is importing them into the main CSS which is, just, weird.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is mostly a post to make a post. I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking a lot about SFF fandom and how Certain Parties just seem so intent on stirring shit up with their ridiculous s&amp;mdash;-core concept, something which defines a &lt;em>negative&lt;/em> and not what they&amp;rsquo;re doing, which is a lot of body horror. I don&amp;rsquo;t think SFF necessarily needs more body horror, thanks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also, these people don&amp;rsquo;t actually seem to be very widely read in SFF and therefore think that no one is reading or writing &amp;ldquo;dark&amp;rdquo; fiction and well, that&amp;rsquo;s a crock of shit. And they&amp;rsquo;re &lt;em>very&lt;/em> intent on lionizing GRRM for some reason. I don&amp;rsquo;t know why.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyhow, I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a lot of thinking about this whole thing for the past few months and I&amp;rsquo;m hoping, at some point, to be able to write something coherent about it as opposed to what I&amp;rsquo;ve just written.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And now? It&amp;rsquo;s time for me to get to work! Work! How glorious it is to be able to work at a job that I really enjoy and that I seem to be reasonably good at? I mean, still a newbie developer, but I&amp;rsquo;m learning and seem to be learning fast enough.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>