<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>sff on Peculiar Monster</title>
    <link>https://peculiar.monster/tags/sff/</link>
    <description>Recent content in sff on Peculiar Monster</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://peculiar.monster/images/logo.png</url>
      <link>https://peculiar.monster/images/logo.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 22:15:34 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://peculiar.monster/tags/sff/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Coding and Thinking</title>
      <link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/coding-and-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 22:15:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/coding-and-thinking/</guid>
      <description>Did you know that I have not one, but two kanban boards? One for getting this site set up as I want it to be, and another for mothballing my old site.
They both have a LOT of things on them. It&amp;rsquo;s gonna be a lot of work.
But this evening, I knocked out a fair number of backend things I wanted to fix on this site, primarily with the CSS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>F Stands for Fungible</title>
      <link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/f-stands-for-fungible/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 16:55:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/f-stands-for-fungible/</guid>
      <description>I started the process of mothballing my old site last night.
It was really hard to go through nearly 700 posts and unpublish them, leaving only the ones I&amp;rsquo;m planning on archiving on a static site.
Really, really hard. Also hard was seeing people respond on Twitter to my statement a few days ago that I was shutting the site down.
It&amp;rsquo;s been, personally, a terrible few years. I&amp;rsquo;ve lost my health, my career, and now I&amp;rsquo;m losing the vast majority of my social network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Current Feelings Towards SFF Fandom</title>
      <link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/sff-feelings-mood/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 13:25:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/sff-feelings-mood/</guid>
      <description>This is a fairly accurate description of how I&amp;rsquo;m currently feeling about SFF fandom. Burn it all down, my children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Thoughts (June 9)</title>
      <link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/random-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 09:52:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/random-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>Oof. I went in for my monthly-ish paracentesis yesterday morning.
If you don&amp;rsquo;t know what this is, here&amp;rsquo;s a handy explainer from Wikipedia.
First of all, I was up entirely too early for my own good. But it did mean I was able to take my meds and eat breakfast before having to leave for the hospital, so that&amp;rsquo;s something, yes?
Normally, it&amp;rsquo;s not too bad, but the doctor doing them yesterday was a resident and while she was very nice and perfectly competent, she was also still a resident, which means that she wasn&amp;rsquo;t as skilled as some of the doctors who have been there for years.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
