<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>coding on Peculiar Monster</title>
    <link>https://peculiar.monster/categories/coding/</link>
    <description>Recent content in coding on Peculiar Monster</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://peculiar.monster/images/logo.png</url>
      <link>https://peculiar.monster/images/logo.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 12:02:13 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://peculiar.monster/categories/coding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s Been Busy Around Here</title>
      <link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/its-been-busy-around-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 12:02:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/its-been-busy-around-here/</guid>
      <description>It has been a week here.
I have:
 successfully wrangled custom radio button hover and focus states  the html radio buttons were offset from the custom ones and moving them helped the hover happen in the right places I am still mad at whoever originally coded the component, though   got a chunk of coding done for the mobile version of the site footer  the desktop version is good to go, but I have a few more bootstrap/flexbox things to figure out   helped a user regain access to their account using nothing more than an old photograph of their phone&amp;rsquo;s screen and a vague list of tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Messing Around</title>
      <link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/messing-around/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 00:38:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/messing-around/</guid>
      <description>So here I am, in the wee hours of the morning, having frittered away the last 7 hours of my life on a few &amp;ldquo;quick&amp;rdquo; updates to the site.
Except I kept thinking of new ways to do things or fixing errors with the style sheets to the point where, except for the general layout and the little cactus icon up there (which is going to be replaced soon, I swear), it&amp;rsquo;s basically a whole new theme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Ridiculous Day</title>
      <link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/ridiculous-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 22:02:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/ridiculous-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s been a day of a lot of ridiculous all over the board.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code, Why Are You Like This?</title>
      <link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/code-why-are-you-like-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 11:35:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/code-why-are-you-like-this/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;And of course, no sooner than I finished my previous post and decided to deploy the site than I ran into a bunch of problems, some bigger than others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I had to set the DNS record to point at GitHub Pages. And that takes time to propogate and I am &lt;em&gt;impatient&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The DNS wasn&amp;rsquo;t propogating and GH was tellng me that I&amp;rsquo;d configured something wrong, so it recommended that I set &lt;code&gt;A&lt;/code&gt; records to point at the GitHub Pages IP addresses&amp;hellip;except it didn&amp;rsquo;t actually link to where I could &lt;em&gt;find&lt;/em&gt; those IP addresses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally found them buried in GH&amp;rsquo;s documentation, but I&amp;rsquo;ll be damned if I can find the page again, even with searching through my browser history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also set up the &lt;code&gt;CNAME&lt;/code&gt; record at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I had to set up the GitHub workflow to actually deploy from my repo to the page&amp;ndash;and unbeknownst to me, there was a &lt;em&gt;critical&lt;/em&gt; piece of missing information from the workflow as written.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that piece of information was setting &lt;code&gt;cname: peculiar.monster&lt;/code&gt; in the deploy script.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seriously. &lt;code&gt;CNAME&lt;/code&gt; kept on disappearing from the &lt;code&gt;gh-pages&lt;/code&gt; branch and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out why until I looked at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/marketplace/actions/github-pages-action#%EF%B8%8F-add-cname-file-cname&#34;&gt;this GH Action&lt;/a&gt; which mentioned setting &lt;code&gt;CNAME&lt;/code&gt;, while &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/marketplace/actions/hugo-setup&#34;&gt;the Hugo-specific action&lt;/a&gt;&amp;ndash;the one I chose to use&amp;ndash;did not mention it anywhere. No wonder it was being removed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, with that sorted, I turned my attention to why either the theme or Hugo wasn&amp;rsquo;t respecting my `&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
