<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Peculiar Monster</title><link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Peculiar Monster</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>GigaMeow</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 11:12:46 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://peculiar.monster/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Art of Losing</title><link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/the-art-of-losing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 11:12:46 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/the-art-of-losing/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-art-of-losing">The Art of Losing&lt;/h1>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>The art of losing isn’t hard to master;&lt;br>
so many things seem filled with the intent&lt;br>
to be lost that their loss is no disaster.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>Four years ago today, I almost died.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And while I didn&amp;rsquo;t lose my life, I have had to &lt;a href="https://www.poetryfoundation.org/poems/47536/one-art">master the art of losing&lt;/a> nonetheless.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="first">First&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The first thing I lost was my health. I&amp;rsquo;d been almost &lt;em>rudely&lt;/em> healthy up to that point. I&amp;rsquo;d never been seriously sick beyond a couple of bouts of flu in my 20&amp;rsquo;s. I had the occasional migraine and I&amp;rsquo;d generally get a cold or three in the winter, but in terms of physical illness, not much beyond the time I broke &lt;a href="https://radiopaedia.org/articles/smith-fracture">my wrist&lt;/a> when I was 9.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So dealing with a sudden onset situation that I didn&amp;rsquo;t understand beyond &amp;ldquo;you have &lt;a href="https://www.hopkinsmedicine.org/health/conditions-and-diseases/gallstone-pancreatitis">gallstone pancreatitis&lt;/a> but it should clear up pretty soon.&amp;rdquo; Spoiler: it did not. It was 3 months before it was &amp;ldquo;cleared up&amp;rdquo; and during that three months my pancreas decided it would be fun to digest itself. This is &lt;em>really really really&lt;/em> painful. And I wasn&amp;rsquo;t getting enough pain medication.&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>All &lt;a href="https://www.hopkinsmedicine.org/health/conditions-and-diseases/acute-pancreatitis/acute-pancreatitis-treatment">the complications&lt;/a> that Johns Hopkins lists for pancreatitis? I had &lt;em>all&lt;/em> of them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And my medical team was composed of a bunch of surgical residents whose attending wasn&amp;rsquo;t supervising them properly. They discharged me multiple times when they should not; one time sending me home with &lt;em>55 pounds of fluid&lt;/em> and telling me that it would &amp;ldquo;resolve on its own&amp;rdquo; and spoiler: it did not. It put me into renal failure.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was only when my GI doctor came on the scene about two months into my illness that things started to change. He or someone from his office came by every day during daylight hours to talk to me and let me know what the plan was. He removed a 15 cm section of dead pancreas endoscopically&amp;ndash;and that was what really helped me to turn the corner and get well enough to be discharged.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyhow. Necrotizing pancreatitis is incredibly painful and I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t wish it on my worst enemy. I take 13 different medications on a daily basis and they&amp;rsquo;re all essential to my continued existence on the plane of the living. I have eight different doctors that I see on a regular basis and all the required medical tests that go along with that. Between July 2018 and February 2021, I was hospitalized 18 times and most of those times were for at least a week.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Since I really don&amp;rsquo;t have a pancreas anymore, I&amp;rsquo;m also on the diabetes merry-go-round,&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> which so far has involved a Durable Medical Equipment supplier (DME) sitting on the order for my insulin pump for &lt;em>five months&lt;/em> because they needed me to sign the financial responsibility form&amp;ndash;except they weren&amp;rsquo;t actually telling me that, they were telling me that they needed my insurance to provide a form that didn&amp;rsquo;t exist. I had to get a healthcare advocate involved to resolve the situation. I&amp;rsquo;ve had to call my mail order pharmacy multiple times to try to get them to send me my insulin. I had a &lt;em>different&lt;/em> DME demand a $700 up-front payment when I changed insurance because they didn&amp;rsquo;t take down the correct information when they validated my insurance and decided that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t fulfilled any of my deductible yet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am still not resigned to the loss of my health, even though I know that my current level of wellness is about as good as it&amp;rsquo;s going to get.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="second">Second&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Then there was my career. When I got sick, my career was on the upswing: I was a recognized expert throughout the company in my specific niche, I was on a team that was developing the process for the spin-off company I was slated to go to, and things were just really, really good.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I returned to work in November 2018 and for the next year, I worked to get back to full capacity. In September of 2019, I was transferred to a new manager, someone who had previously been a peer. I thought things would be fine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then came my performance review for 2019, which she somehow managed to hijack despite only being my manager for &lt;em>one month&lt;/em> when I turned in my self-evaluation. She somehow managed to steamroll my former manager&amp;ndash;he was obviously pretty mad about it&amp;ndash;and somehow managed to give me the lowest possible performance rating but didn&amp;rsquo;t put any of the Serious Problems in writing and got around putting me on a PIP.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let me put it this way: the two years before I got sick, I&amp;rsquo;d gotten the highest possible performance review which was unheard of, so to go from that to the lowest in literally two years &lt;em>should&lt;/em> have raised a bunch of flags with HR, but it didn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My manager told me that 2020 would be a &amp;ldquo;reset&amp;rdquo; year for me and I was fool enough to believe her.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In February 2020, I went to the on-site nurse with the paperwork from my doctors for ADA accommodations. My manager was notified and she was able to convene a shadow HR process called a &amp;ldquo;Medical Review Board&amp;rdquo; in which my need to work 2 days a week from home so I could conserve my energy for actually working instead of commuting was denied. At the time, there were three people in my role under this manager. One of them was a full time work from home employee in Canada. I am on the East Coast, and the other was in Iowa, at the same location as our manager. There was literally no need for me to be in the office except for the one in person meeting I had with IT each month.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On February 27, 2020, I was told that I was being put on indefinite disability leave because my accommodations were an undue burden on the business. They essentially read the paperwork with the worst possible interpretation and did not look at how I&amp;rsquo;d been using my FMLA time outside of hospitalizations&amp;ndash;I was averaging 11 hours a month, which was not excessive. We all know what happened two weeks later&amp;ndash;everyone who could was working from home.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And none of this was put in writing. So when I went to my doctors to ask them to revise my accommodations, it looked like &lt;em>I&lt;/em> initiated the change. I think, at this point, my manager was hoping I&amp;rsquo;d go out permanently on long term disability.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Instead, I was back to work by the beginning of April. And I started documenting &lt;em>everything&lt;/em> I was doing to achieve my goals. I was color coding every single hour I was working so I could show that I was actually working.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I thought things were holding together and that I was making good progress&amp;ndash;and that&amp;rsquo;s what my manager was telling me while at the same time she was telling me that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t have a monthly call with a peer to talk about instructional design, even though I was going to be responsible for writing a lot of technical documentation in 2021.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was also doing the main part of my job, despite significant barriers around getting the data I needed because instead of letting me be in charge of the reconciliation from beginning to end, she made me rely on my two colleagues who were &lt;em>always&lt;/em> late or revising numbers from previous months.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every time I told our manager that they were consistently putting me in a position where I was re-doing work multiple times, she emphasized how busy they were.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Every time I told her how difficult I was finding my workload, she would laugh and tell me hers was worse and then about a week later she&amp;rsquo;d find another special project to dump in my lap.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I stopped mentioning it to her. I also stopped taking lunch breaks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was hospitalized three times between late September and mid-December for sepsis. Specifically, I had a bacterial infection in my blood. That&amp;rsquo;s incredibly serious. Me being out was a serious problem for my manager, as my two colleagues didn&amp;rsquo;t even try to pick up any of my tasks, even though I covered for them when they took vacations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So when review time rolled around again, despite the eight pages of accomplishments, she rated me as low as possible &lt;em>again&lt;/em>. And again, didn&amp;rsquo;t provide any sort of substantive critique in writing. If my work was so poor all year long, why wasn&amp;rsquo;t I on a PIP? Why were there no written reprimands in my record?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then she &lt;em>lied to my face&lt;/em> about this making me vulnerable if layoffs were to happen. I was laid off a week later as part of a mass layoff, where nearly everyone else who was laid off was at least 10 years older than me and had at least 15 years of service more than I did and were making a lot more money.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>She gaslit me, she isolated me, she shifted the goalposts, she made constant appeals to authority, and the result was that she not only destroyed the reputation I&amp;rsquo;d spent most of two decades building but also my confidence in my own competence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I should have seen that &lt;a href="https://issendai.livejournal.com/572510.html">I was enmeshed in a sick system&lt;/a>, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t. And it took me most of last year to dig myself out of the hole I found myself in.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="third">Third&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Last year&amp;rsquo;s Hugo season and the aftermath was incredibly difficult, especially as it happened as I was in the middle of grieving both my health and career loss.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was a finalist because I wrote an essay that used Very Strong Language to call out a Venerable and Wealthy Older White Man for making the Hugo ceremony in 2020 about himself and how great things used to be instead of calling attention to the incredible slate of finalists and their accomplishments. And people put it on their nominating ballots.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There was a segment of fandom that thought my essay had caused this Venerable Personage to cancel his plans to attend Worldcon in 2021 (not likely, his next book is like decades overdue at this point) and that was Very Bad. There was also some folks having the vapors over whether or not my nomination was a violation of the convention&amp;rsquo;s Code of Conduct (it wasn&amp;rsquo;t) to the point where they decided to try to drop the internet on my head.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And that would have been dealable, it truly would have, as the main actors where already people I knew to be assholes of the highest order.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s what happened &lt;em>after&lt;/em> the Hugo ceremony that did me in.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A large multinational company that has made a lot of things was the sponsor of the Red Carpet and there was a branded backdrop and a logo in the program book at the awards ceremony and they were thanked at the end of the ceremony along with the other sponsors.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One of the things this company makes is missiles and drones. And they also help make various NASA programs happen. A &lt;em>lot&lt;/em> of multinationals operate in different markets with products that both benefit and harm humanity. I made the mistake of mentioning on Twitter that one of my partners works at this multinational as part of a conversation between myself and two other people&amp;ndash;in other words, I didn&amp;rsquo;t just bust out with it on my timeline, it was buried in replies and wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been surfaced by the algorithm for most folks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Folks looking to gain a bit of clout were doing indiscriminate searches for the name of the company and found my tweet and well, &lt;a href="https://www.rewire.org/context-collapse-online/">context collapsed on me&lt;/a>. I found myself under siege by the same group of individuals who brigaded another writer off Twitter in December 2021. I found my words being quoted derisively in a podcast that claimed to be about a non-existent trend they&amp;rsquo;d noticed in SFF and calling out two prominent and Very Online White Male SFF Writers as the problem when really they were using the non-existent trend and the engagement they knew they&amp;rsquo;d get from at least one of the writers mentioned by name as cover to continue to harass me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And no one stood up for me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Okay, that isn&amp;rsquo;t exactly true: other &lt;em>fans&lt;/em> stood up for me. But in terms of platform and reach, all the people with those things&amp;ndash;people who I&amp;rsquo;ve attended conventions with, broken bread with, paneled with&amp;ndash;none of them said anything. For the most part, they didn&amp;rsquo;t even &lt;em>notice&lt;/em> that I was being harassed because the entire discussion was dominated by how stupid their non-existent trend is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And my heart broke into a million pieces when I realized how invisible I was because I was merely a &lt;em>fan&lt;/em>. And as everyone knows, we&amp;rsquo;re &lt;a href="https://peculiar.monster/posts/f-stands-for-fungible/">fungible&lt;/a> .&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="end">End&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I am here. I am alive. I am filling in the holes in my life (and getting &lt;a href="https://wandering.shop/@eilatan/108681555961694221">new holes in my head&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And yet: I have so far to go&amp;ndash;&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;It’s evident&lt;br>
the art of losing’s not too hard to master&lt;br>
though it may look like (&lt;em>Write&lt;/em> it!) like disaster.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;section class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
&lt;hr>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
&lt;p>The hospital I was in has a policy of not actively offering pain medication. You have to ask for it. They&amp;rsquo;re supposed to write on the patient info board when your last dose was, but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t happen. So I spent a &lt;em>lot&lt;/em> of time in excruciating pain. Because, like, I was barely capable of talking for the first month I was sick because I&amp;rsquo;d had &lt;a href="https://www.hopkinsmedicine.org/health/conditions-and-diseases/subarachnoid-hemorrhage">a fucking &lt;em>stroke&lt;/em>&lt;/a> and they were expecting me to be able to &lt;em>tell time&lt;/em>?&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:2" role="doc-endnote">
&lt;p>But not really the &lt;a href="https://pancreasfoundation.org/patient-information/ailments-pancreas/exocrine-pancreatic-insufficiency-epi/">exocrine pancreatic insufficiency&lt;/a> one&amp;ndash;I have the medication for it, but I don&amp;rsquo;t take it that often.&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/section></description></item><item><title>This Meatsuit is Annoying</title><link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/this-meatsuit-is-annoying/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 16:04:19 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/this-meatsuit-is-annoying/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am just not feeling the thing this week.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I had a mere 2.5L drained last week&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> and you&amp;rsquo;d think that would have helped and&amp;ndash;nope.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I feel bloated and I basically haven&amp;rsquo;t felt hungry so there&amp;rsquo;s been a lot of forcing myself to eat and then I feel like I overate and it&amp;rsquo;s just not pleasant.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And I&amp;rsquo;m having weird random pain in my gut, but not enough to actually call my doctor or go to the ER about. It&amp;rsquo;s been a year and a half since I was hospitalized and my therapist has reminded me that this streak isn&amp;rsquo;t unbreakable, alas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve also started a new blood thinner, Xarelto. I&amp;rsquo;d been on Eliquis since 2018 and then my prescription insurance (everyone&amp;rsquo;s favorite, Caremark/CVS) decided to take it off the formulary and require a prior authorization so my doctor just switched me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The funny thing is that because of all the hospitalizations I&amp;rsquo;ve had, I have one heck of a stockpile of medication, so I had 6 months of Eliquis to use up before I started the Xarelto. And I can tell the difference: I&amp;rsquo;d bleed a bit more than I&amp;rsquo;d like when I got a cut or scratch, but the Xarelto? Hooboy. I accidentally scratched my arm the other day and bled all over two shirts before it stopped.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then I was scratching my leg yesterday and accidentally hit a couple of scabs and actual blood dripping down my leg happened, so I stuck a band-aid on and when I took it off before bed last night, I looked at it and there was quite a bit of blood happening.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And to continue on the blood theme, I had to get labs done in advance of my seeing my specialist in Center City next week,&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> and I decided to go to the hospital instead of Labcorp. Which actually worked out well: I told the phlebotamist that I was a hard stick and she proceeded to find the one good vein in my arm and get it on the first try and she wanted to know who&amp;rsquo;d told me I was a hard stick. My answer? &amp;ldquo;Every other phlebotamist in this hospital and all of the ones at LabCorp, too.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve a band-aid on my arm and I&amp;rsquo;m a little scared to take it off, even though it&amp;rsquo;s been nearly 7 hours. I gotta say, though, it was &lt;em>nice&lt;/em> to be able to get in and out of the lab like a normal person. Instead of having every phlebotamist in the place taking a (literal) stab at me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But. I feel like hot garbage and I&amp;rsquo;ve been taking too many naps and I don&amp;rsquo;t know what to do about it. I&amp;rsquo;ll figure something out, I&amp;rsquo;m sure.&lt;/p>
&lt;section class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
&lt;hr>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
&lt;p>This isn&amp;rsquo;t very much, I was regularly getting 6 to 8 liters drained a year and a half ago.&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:2" role="doc-endnote">
&lt;p>He&amp;rsquo;s going to tell me that there&amp;rsquo;s nothing more to be done and to hold the course; why I have to spend an hour and a half in the car and $20 on parking to be told that, I don&amp;rsquo;t know.&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/section></description></item><item><title>It's Been Busy Around Here</title><link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/its-been-busy-around-here/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 12:02:13 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/its-been-busy-around-here/</guid><description>&lt;p>It has been a &lt;em>week&lt;/em> here.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>successfully wrangled custom radio button hover and focus states
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the html radio buttons were offset from the custom ones and moving them helped the hover happen in the right places&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I am still mad at whoever originally coded the component, though&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>got a chunk of coding done for the mobile version of the site footer
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the desktop version is good to go, but I have a few more bootstrap/flexbox things to figure out&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>helped a user regain access to their account using nothing more than an old photograph of their phone&amp;rsquo;s screen and a vague list of tasks. I felt like a fucking wizard.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>installed &lt;a href="https://www.11ty.dev">11ty&lt;/a> to use for the Pretty Terrible archive
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>it&amp;rsquo;s mostly done, but I&amp;rsquo;m still messing with the css and attempting to get some data to show up the way I&amp;rsquo;d like it to&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I also need to pull the images that the posts I&amp;rsquo;m keeping need&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>managed to write an &lt;code>npm start&lt;/code> script for the 11ty site which launches the local server and runs sass so I can map color hex codes to variables along with other things
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>this makes me happy, because it&amp;rsquo;s easier to change colors uses sass variables&lt;/li>
&lt;li>also, the easier the command is for me to launch something on the command line, the happier I am&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I&amp;rsquo;m now trying to figure out how to do this for some of my personal Habitica scripts&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>fiddled with the template here a tiny bit, but not as much as I&amp;rsquo;d like&lt;/li>
&lt;li>thought about changing the template here, but the sunk cost fallacy has come into play so I don&amp;rsquo;t know&lt;/li>
&lt;li>finished re-reading Katherine Addison&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>The Goblin Emperor&lt;/em> and I&amp;rsquo;m now re-reading &lt;em>Witness for the Dead&lt;/em> and I&amp;rsquo;ll probably re-read &lt;em>Grief of Stones&lt;/em>, too&amp;ndash;I have an essay started about that one, so I do want to be sure of the themes, etc.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>beat Tetris Effects Journey mode on Beginner&lt;/li>
&lt;li>called the local hospital system to make sure that all my bills are accounted for in the billing system and figured out how to access my account online; they keep changing systems (MAKE UP YOUR MINDS, PEOPLE) and access is a constant struggle and they are constantly sending me paper bills&lt;/li>
&lt;li>paid a lingering Labcorp bill&lt;/li>
&lt;li>paid my therapist&lt;/li>
&lt;li>paid the household bills and balanced the household budget
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>this included re-registering my car and filing the deed which came in the mail since my car is all paid off now&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>messaged my GI doctor about medical marijuana&lt;/li>
&lt;li>did a bunch of knitting
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>I had to more or less rip out a mostly-complete project that had been in hibernation for at least five years due to breaks in the yarn&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It was weird, the breaks were &lt;em>only&lt;/em> in the gray yarn and not the variegated, so I don&amp;rsquo;t know what happened&lt;/li>
&lt;li>BUT on the plus side, I&amp;rsquo;ve done way more of this designer&amp;rsquo;s patterns in the time between putting this project in hibernation and now, so the bits I was struggling with that made me shove this in a bag and forget about it aren&amp;rsquo;t really an issue anymore&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>I still have a few things to do today. I have an appointment for a paracentesis this afternoon. I was planning on working between therapy and shortly before I had to leave, but I woke up this morning feeling like utter garbage so bailed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Miles has been very attentive&amp;ndash;he knows when I&amp;rsquo;m not feeling well and will pester me to go to bed. I think that&amp;rsquo;s what his attentiveness this morning was about, but he has since given up and is napping on his perch by the front window.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also gave in and purchased an Amazon spy speaker. My SIL has them in her house and it was really convenient to just be able to ask it to play music or to tell me when an hour had passed. Yes, I know this is how they get you. I am probably going to get a couple more on Prime Day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Weekend plans include more fussing with 11ty and the PT archive and probably more work on this site&amp;rsquo;s template. I&amp;rsquo;m also going to go all out and knit, play Animal Crossing, and do some laundry. I know, my life is so exciting!&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The land that never has been yet—</title><link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/the-land-that-never-has-been-yet/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 16:48:39 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/the-land-that-never-has-been-yet/</guid><description>&lt;p>Langston Hughes said it better than I can, especially for this 4th of July, one where we&amp;rsquo;re reeling from the endgame of a culture war that started before I was born.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;h1 id="let-america-be-america-again">Let America Be America Again&lt;/h1>
&lt;p>Let America be America again.&lt;br>
Let it be the dream it used to be.&lt;br>
Let it be the pioneer on the plain&lt;br>
Seeking a home where he himself is free.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(America never was America to me.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let America be the dream the dreamers dreamed—&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let it be that great strong land of love&lt;br>
Where never kings connive nor tyrants scheme&lt;br>
That any man be crushed by one above.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(It never was America to me.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>O, let my land be a land where Liberty&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Is crowned with no false patriotic wreath,&lt;br>
But opportunity is real, and life is free,&lt;br>
Equality is in the air we breathe.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>(There’s never been equality for me,&lt;br>
Nor freedom in this “homeland of the free.”)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;em>Say, who are you that mumbles in the dark?&lt;/em>&lt;br>
&lt;em>And who are you that draws your veil across the stars?&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am the poor white, fooled and pushed apart,&lt;br>
I am the Negro bearing slavery’s scars.&lt;br>
I am the red man driven from the land,&lt;br>
I am the immigrant clutching the hope I seek—&lt;br>
And finding only the same old stupid plan&lt;br>
Of dog eat dog, of mighty crush the weak.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am the young man, full of strength and hope,&lt;br>
Tangled in that ancient endless chain&lt;br>
Of profit, power, gain, of grab the land!&lt;br>
Of grab the gold! Of grab the ways of satisfying need!&lt;br>
Of work the men! Of take the pay!&lt;br>
Of owning everything for one’s own greed!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am the farmer, bondsman to the soil.&lt;br>
I am the worker sold to the machine.&lt;br>
I am the Negro, servant to you all.&lt;br>
I am the people, humble, hungry, mean—&lt;br>
Hungry yet today despite the dream.&lt;br>
Beaten yet today—O, Pioneers!&lt;br>
I am the man who never got ahead,&lt;br>
The poorest worker bartered through the years.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yet I’m the one who dreamt our basic dream&lt;br>
In the Old World while still a serf of kings,&lt;br>
Who dreamt a dream so strong, so brave, so true,&lt;br>
That even yet its mighty daring sings&lt;br>
In every brick and stone, in every furrow turned&lt;br>
That’s made America the land it has become.&lt;br>
O, I’m the man who sailed those early seas&lt;br>
In search of what I meant to be my home—&lt;br>
For I’m the one who left dark Ireland’s shore,&lt;br>
And Poland’s plain, and England’s grassy lea,&lt;br>
And torn from Black Africa’s strand I came&lt;br>
To build a “homeland of the free.”&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The free?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Who said the free? Not me?&lt;br>
Surely not me? The millions on relief today?&lt;br>
The millions shot down when we strike?&lt;br>
The millions who have nothing for our pay?&lt;br>
For all the dreams we’ve dreamed&lt;br>
And all the songs we’ve sung&lt;br>
And all the hopes we’ve held&lt;br>
And all the flags we’ve hung,&lt;br>
The millions who have nothing for our pay—&lt;br>
Except the dream that’s almost dead today.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>O, let America be America again—&lt;br>
The land that never has been yet—&lt;br>
And yet must be—the land where &lt;em>every&lt;/em> man is free.&lt;br>
The land that’s mine—the poor man’s, Indian’s, Negro’s, ME—&lt;br>
Who made America,&lt;br>
Whose sweat and blood, whose faith and pain,&lt;br>
Whose hand at the foundry, whose plow in the rain,&lt;br>
Must bring back our mighty dream again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sure, call me any ugly name you choose—&lt;br>
The steel of freedom does not stain.&lt;br>
From those who live like leeches on the people’s lives,&lt;br>
We must take back our land again,&lt;br>
America!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>O, yes,&lt;br>
I say it plain,&lt;br>
America never was America to me,&lt;br>
And yet I swear this oath—&lt;br>
America will be!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Out of the rack and ruin of our gangster death,&lt;br>
The rape and rot of graft, and stealth, and lies,&lt;br>
We, the people, must redeem&lt;br>
The land, the mines, the plants, the rivers.&lt;br>
The mountains and the endless plain—&lt;br>
All, all the stretch of these great green states—&lt;br>
And make America again!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;ndash;&lt;em>Langston Hughes&lt;/em>&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote></description></item><item><title>Thoughts on Digital Gardening and Information Organization</title><link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/thoughts-on-digital-gardening-and-information-organization/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 16:40:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/thoughts-on-digital-gardening-and-information-organization/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending a lot of time over the last week falling into various rabbit holes. So many.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But one thing I keep coming back to is how, on my previous blog, I felt paralyzed by the weight of perfection. As if I were under so much scrutiny that the smallest mistake would cause a shitstorm.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This feeling was only exacerbated by the fact that when I did say something stupid on Twitter, a group of leftier than thou folks who enjoy brigading other people for the tiniest of ideological differences decided to brigade me. And suddenly: I found that I was unable to speak in that space any longer&amp;ndash;that the &lt;a href="https://peculiar.monster/posts/f-is-for-fungible/">years of abuse&lt;/a> had simply destroyed my ability to write or engage at all in that space.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That&amp;rsquo;s the lens I have been looking through as I read through all these different essays and short pieces about being a person on the internet.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first big concept I find myself intrigued by is that of digital gardening. &lt;a href="https://maggieappleton.com">Maggie Appleton&lt;/a> has written a fair bit about this; I found her &lt;a href="https://maggieappleton.com/garden-history">brief history of digital gardening&lt;/a> extremely informative and honestly, quite fascinating:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>A garden is a collection of evolving ideas that aren&amp;rsquo;t strictly organised by their publication date. They&amp;rsquo;re inherently exploratory – notes are linked through contextual associations. They aren&amp;rsquo;t refined or complete - notes are published as half-finished thoughts that will grow and evolve over time. They&amp;rsquo;re less rigid, less performative, and less perfect than the personal websites we&amp;rsquo;re used to seeing.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I ended up reading a lot of the different essays on her site and found a lot of food for thought and I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how I&amp;rsquo;m going to integrate some of these concepts into this site, but I like the idea of getting away from the chronological blog post sort of situation.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So the second concept is around Amy Hoy&amp;rsquo;s essay on &lt;a href="https://stackingthebricks.com/how-blogs-broke-the-web/">how the blog broke the web&lt;/a>, rings very true to me despite there being a great honking factual error in it:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>[Movable Type] &amp;hellip;was also the first web-based CMS that you could download for free, install, and run on your own web host.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>In fact, it was not the first. There was &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Greymatter_(software)">Greymatter&lt;/a> (which I used) and possibly some other systems&amp;ndash;Blogger was around at that time, but my hazy memory is that it was a royal pain in the ass to use, as the FTP portion of the software was fairly flaky.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>At any rate, I think Amy Hoy is onto something in this essay: the fact that Movable Type was incredibly powerful &lt;em>and&lt;/em> under constant development made it irresistible for folks who wanted to create personal websites but didn&amp;rsquo;t want to deal with hand-coding everything. I remember that the templates were fairly easy to customize and you could import and export entries as part of the built in functionality. There wasn&amp;rsquo;t a large or robust plug-in community like there is with what ultimately came to dominate the blogging software world: WordPress.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Movable Type is still around, but I know of only two blogs which still use it: &lt;a href="https://nielsenhayden.com/makinglight/index.html">Making Light&lt;/a>, on a very old and lovingly maintained version on which it appears that the CSS is currently not working, and &lt;a href="https://www.kottke.org/">Kottke&lt;/a>, who uses it but doesn&amp;rsquo;t specify if he&amp;rsquo;s using the commercial version or the open source version (the latter of which you have to do a &lt;em>lot&lt;/em> of hunting for &lt;a href="https://movabletype.org/downloads/stable/">in order to find&lt;/a>).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Around the time of the great brouhaha around MT licensing happened, I was maintaining both my MT site and a LiveJournal. I eventually abandoned the MT site and wrote exclusively on LiveJournal until it was sold to the Russians, at which point I made all my posts private and stopped writing there.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But I digress. Hoy&amp;rsquo;s central thesis is that tools like Movable Type were the thin part of the wedge that forced large chunks of the web into a reverse-chronological hellscape, a wedge the prioritized form over function: instead of allowing users to set up their sites however they wanted, the way you could when you were coding HTML by hand, you could make of of two choices. Here&amp;rsquo;s Hoy on that:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Homepage production became suddenly a question of economics:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Go with the system’s default format: zero work.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Customizing the system to your format: way more work than pure HTML ever was&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>And who, once offered a path of least resistance, has the energy to fight it all the way?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The format won.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was easier — faster! — to literally go with the flow… of &lt;em>time&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>I really can&amp;rsquo;t disagree with this: I remember spending hours tweaking my templates so they were just right.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But at least you &lt;em>could&lt;/em>. Have you ever tried to modify a WordPress template? Not customize the stylesheet, but the actual template itself? Good luck. They&amp;rsquo;re a maze of PHP with includes and god knows what else. And extraordinarily vulnerable to various exploits, including one that injected malicious JavaScript on my site and forced me to change templates about this time last year. An entire industry sprung up around frameworks&amp;ndash;I mean &amp;ldquo;parent themes&amp;rdquo;&amp;ndash;to optimize SEO and providing different hooks you could use to customize the functionality without touching much code.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But really, it was just &lt;em>easier&lt;/em> to go with the templates that came with WordPress, to go with that flow, so every new blog looked the same. Hell, if you look at one of the most influential blogs in the SFF world, it&amp;rsquo;s using a barely modified stock WordPress theme, to the point where it&amp;rsquo;s just pathetic and laughable. The owner of the site has won a number of Hugos for it, you would think that he&amp;rsquo;d be able to get someone to make him a pretty site.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another thing that came with WordPress was the plug-in community. There are a lot of plugins to enable what should be basic functionality: contact pages, dynamic tables, spam protection and other site security measures, and so on and so forth. And the problem with these plug-ins is that they have become a source of revenue for the folks who make them, so there&amp;rsquo;s usually a freemium version as well as a paid one. I don&amp;rsquo;t like the security and privacy implications of this model.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But the big advantage WordPress has, especially the hosted WordPress.com service has is that it just works. You can create a blog and be up and running in a matter of minutes. There&amp;rsquo;s very little configuration to do and no template system to learn (unless you want to).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Whereas the amount of time it took me to get &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/">Hugo&lt;/a> up and running&amp;ndash;well, Hugo installed easily enough on my machines, but you also have to have a working knowledge of git, GitHub, and an understanding of the different options to deploy the working site. It took me quite a while to get the deploy script working because the instructions omitted setting &lt;code>CNAME&lt;/code> on the &lt;code>gh-pages&lt;/code> branch of my repo&amp;ndash;but I was able to see that that was an issue.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There are &lt;em>significant&lt;/em> technical barriers involved with using a static site generator for a blog: you have to be comfortable getting into the nuts and bolts of the templates and learn how to write a variant of &lt;a href="https://go.dev/">Go&lt;/a>, which is a language I had no familiarity with prior to starting this project. I am &lt;em>still&lt;/em> struggling to get pagination working.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But I find this sort of work satisfying and I&amp;rsquo;m able to surmount the gaps in my technical knowledge through sheer stubbornness, a willingness to make mistakes, and making liberal use of a search engine. Not everyone does. Most folks want an out of the box tool that just works.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And the third concept and probably the most important one is from &lt;a href="https://matthiasott.com/notes/just-put-stuff-out-there">this essay&lt;/a> by Matthias Ott: Just put stuff out there:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Maybe, we are overthinking it. Maybe, the one thing we should care most about is just putting stuff out there. At least, this is the primary reason we have a personal website, right? We have it to document and share random thoughts, things we learned, and nuggets we found. If we don’t put stuff out there, why have a website in the first place?&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>Another idea I&amp;rsquo;ve been poking at are personal knowledge bases and different ways of keeping all the threads of my life in some sort of knowledge management system.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m intrigued by the concepts behind Tiago Forte&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://www.buildingasecondbrain.com/">Building a Second Brain&lt;/a> but considering that the website has no mention of how much the course costs and that there&amp;rsquo;s a waitlist for the next cohort, I find that I have very little interest in taking the course.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Instead, &lt;a href="https://maggieappleton.com/basb">I&amp;rsquo;ve looked over Maggie Appleton&amp;rsquo;s notes from several years ago&lt;/a> (and I note that in her disclaimer she mentions the &amp;ldquo;blossoming&amp;rdquo; price which is a hilarious way of describing the inevitable upwards creep of course costs as the instructor/guru becomes more influential) and have come to the conclusion that I&amp;rsquo;ll pick up the book when it comes out in paperback, probably next year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But with this incredibly important caveat: &lt;a href="https://notes.andymatuschak.org/zUMFE66dxeweppDvgbNAb5hukXzXQu8ErVNv">&amp;ldquo;People who write extensively about note-taking rarely have a serious context of use&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a>; that is: most productivity &amp;ldquo;experts&amp;rdquo; primary output is more advice on how to be productive and they are often disconnected from the contexts in which people take and use notes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Until then, the Appleton&amp;rsquo;s sketchnote version is good enough for me to get a reasonable overview. I have a significant file organization problem&amp;ndash;I can usually find things, but I have literally over 30 years of different files stored (in the cloud) and I&amp;rsquo;d like to organize them a bit better and do better with my current working files.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So there&amp;rsquo;s Forte&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://fortelabs.co/blog/para/">PARA system&lt;/a>, where the letters stand for:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>P&lt;/strong>rojects - a specific endpoint or deadline&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>A&lt;/strong>reas of Responsibility - continuous areas of commitment&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>R&lt;/strong>esources - topic or theme of ongoing interest&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&lt;strong>A&lt;/strong>rchive - inactive items from the other categories.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Which, okay, but. It just doesn&amp;rsquo;t seem to provide enough differentiation for me. I like the idea of keeping Resources and clearly identifying my Archive files, however, how to organize within each folder? That&amp;rsquo;s sort of where I stumble. The PARA system calls for there to be no more than 4 levels of organization below each of the 4 major groupings. I don&amp;rsquo;t know.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So a file structure organized with the PARA system would be:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#282a36;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-text" data-lang="text">&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f"> 1&lt;/span>Projects
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f"> 2&lt;/span> Peculiar Monster Redesign 2022
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f"> 3&lt;/span> domain-registration-receipt.pdf
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f"> 4&lt;/span> Research and Inspiration
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f"> 5&lt;/span> Technology 1.md
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f"> 6&lt;/span> Technology 2.md
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f"> 7&lt;/span> Inspiration 1.png
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f"> 8&lt;/span> Research.md
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f"> 9&lt;/span> Design Files
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">10&lt;/span> Images
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">11&lt;/span> Logo Image.png
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">12&lt;/span> Divider Image.png
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">13&lt;/span> Mockups
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">14&lt;/span> Template Mockup.png
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">15&lt;/span> Code
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">16&lt;/span> Tech Stack
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">17&lt;/span> Tech Stack.md
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">18&lt;/span> Styling
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">19&lt;/span> Style.css
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">20&lt;/span> Style2.css
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">21&lt;/span> colors.sass
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">22&lt;/span> Templates
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">23&lt;/span> index.html
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">24&lt;/span> archive.html
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">25&lt;/span> partial-header.html
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">26&lt;/span> partial-footer.html
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">27&lt;/span> JavaScript
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">28&lt;/span> cool script.js
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">29&lt;/span> cooler script.js
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">30&lt;/span> Knitting
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">31&lt;/span> pattern1.pdf
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">32&lt;/span> pattern2.pdf
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">33&lt;/span> Crochet
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">34&lt;/span> pattern1.pdf
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">35&lt;/span> Writing
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">36&lt;/span> poem1.md
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">37&lt;/span> poem2.md
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">38&lt;/span> Essay 1
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">39&lt;/span> essay1.md
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">40&lt;/span> notes.md
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">41&lt;/span> links.md
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">42&lt;/span> Essay 2
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">43&lt;/span> notes.md
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">44&lt;/span>
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">45&lt;/span>Areas
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">46&lt;/span> Medical
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">47&lt;/span> doctors.md
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">48&lt;/span> hospitals.md
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">49&lt;/span> medications.md
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">50&lt;/span> Lab Results
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">51&lt;/span> labcorp 2022-07-01
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">52&lt;/span> Disability Paperwork
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">53&lt;/span> Job #1
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">54&lt;/span> Benefits
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">55&lt;/span> Performance Evaluations
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">56&lt;/span> Paystubs
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">57&lt;/span> 2022-04.pdf
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">58&lt;/span> 2022-05.pdf
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">59&lt;/span>
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">60&lt;/span>Research
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">61&lt;/span> Area of Interest #1
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">62&lt;/span> Area of Interest #2
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">63&lt;/span> Area of Interest #3
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">64&lt;/span>
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">65&lt;/span>Archive
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">66&lt;/span> Peculiar Monster Redesign 2021
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">67&lt;/span> Knitting
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">68&lt;/span> completed pattern1.pdf
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">69&lt;/span> completed pattern2.pdf
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">70&lt;/span> completed pattern3.pdf
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">71&lt;/span> Academic Work
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">72&lt;/span> English Papers
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">73&lt;/span> History Papers
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">74&lt;/span> Writing
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">75&lt;/span> Published Essays
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">76&lt;/span> Trunked
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Then there&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://johnnydecimal.com/">Johnny Decimal&lt;/a>, which I find really, really interesting. It&amp;rsquo;s a lot more granular than the PARA but also has limits. With Johnny Decimal, you use a numbering system to set up ten different areas, and each area can have ten categories beneath it. So you can have a file that look something like this: &lt;code>37.15 Grocery List 2022-07-03&lt;/code> where &lt;code>3&lt;/code> is &lt;code>Household&lt;/code> and &lt;code>7&lt;/code> is &lt;code>Shopping Lists&lt;/code> and &lt;code>15&lt;/code> is the fifteenth item you&amp;rsquo;ve put in that category, so if you want to look at all your household shopping lists, you know to look in your main folder structure for a folder prepended with &lt;code>30.07&lt;/code>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Of course, the problem here is that this doesn&amp;rsquo;t lend itself to keeping track of project-type work, something like &lt;code>redesign website&lt;/code>. One could have a folder called &lt;code>07 - websites&lt;/code> and then a subcategory for each website you have, so &lt;code>07.01 - peculiar monster&lt;/code> for this site, and then you could just add a keyword at the beginning of each redesign-based file: &lt;code>71.25 - redesign notes 2022-006-15.md&lt;/code> and &lt;code>71.32 - redesign style ideas 2022-07-10.md&lt;/code> but then everything&amp;rsquo;s all jumbled together and it would be useful if there were just a way to segregate out projects&amp;ndash;and there is, with a &lt;a href="https://johnnydecimal.com/concepts/multiple-projects/">project-based addition&lt;/a> to the numbering schema: &lt;code>000&lt;/code> through &lt;code>999&lt;/code>, so a Johnny Decimal system with projects might look like this:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#282a36;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-text" data-lang="text">&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f"> 1&lt;/span>100 Life Administration
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f"> 2&lt;/span> 10-19 Administration
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f"> 3&lt;/span> 10 Household Maintenance
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f"> 4&lt;/span> 20-29 Finances
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f"> 5&lt;/span> 21 Taxes
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f"> 6&lt;/span> 22 Mortgage
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f"> 7&lt;/span> 30-39 Medical
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f"> 8&lt;/span> 30 Doctors, Hospitals, and Medications
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f"> 9&lt;/span> 100.30.01 doctors.md
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">10&lt;/span> 100.30.02 hospitals.md
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">11&lt;/span> 100.30.02 medications.md
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">12&lt;/span> 31 Lab Results
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">13&lt;/span> 100.30.01 labcorp 2022-07-01
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">14&lt;/span> 32 Disability Paperwork
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">15&lt;/span> 40-49 Job #1
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">16&lt;/span> 41 Benefits
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">17&lt;/span> 42 Performance Evaluations
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">18&lt;/span> 43 Paystubs
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">19&lt;/span> 100.43.01 2022-04.pdf
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">20&lt;/span> 100.43.02 2022-05.pdf
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">21&lt;/span>
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">22&lt;/span>101 Peculiar Monster Redesign 2022
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">23&lt;/span> 10-19 Administration
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">24&lt;/span> 10 Domain Registration
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">25&lt;/span> 101.10.01 registration receipt.pdf
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">26&lt;/span> 20-29 Research and Inspiration
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">27&lt;/span> 21 Technology 1
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">28&lt;/span> 22 Technology 2
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">29&lt;/span> 23 Inspiration 1
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">30&lt;/span> 24 Research
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">31&lt;/span> 30-39 Design Files
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">32&lt;/span> 31 Images
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">33&lt;/span> 101.31.01 Logo Image.png
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">34&lt;/span> 101.31.01 Divider Image.png
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">35&lt;/span> 32 Mockups
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">36&lt;/span> 101.32.01 Template Mockup.png
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">37&lt;/span> 40-49 Code
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">38&lt;/span> 41 Tech Stack
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">39&lt;/span> 101.41.01 Tech Stack.md
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">40&lt;/span> 42 Styling
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">41&lt;/span> 101.42.01 Style.css
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">42&lt;/span> 101.42.02 Style2.css
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">43&lt;/span> 101.42.03 colors.sass
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">44&lt;/span> 43 Templates
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">45&lt;/span> 101.43.01 index.html
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">46&lt;/span> 101.43.02 archive.html
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">47&lt;/span> 101.43.03 partial-header.html
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">48&lt;/span> 101.43.03 partial-footer.html
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">49&lt;/span> 44 JavaScript
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">50&lt;/span> 101.44.01 cool script.js
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">51&lt;/span> 101.44.01 cooler script.js
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">52&lt;/span>
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">53&lt;/span>102 Textile Art
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">54&lt;/span> 10-19 Knitting Patterns
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">55&lt;/span> 10 Completed
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">56&lt;/span> 11 In Progress
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">57&lt;/span> 12 To Do
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">58&lt;/span> 13 Inspiration
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">59&lt;/span> 20-29 Crochet Patterns
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">60&lt;/span> 21 Completed
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">61&lt;/span> 22 In Progress
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">62&lt;/span> 23 To Do
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">63&lt;/span> 24 Inspiration
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">64&lt;/span>
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Or, with the PARA system you could have a project folder called &lt;code>Peculiar Monster Redesign 2022-07&lt;/code> and then folders for each group of tasks: &lt;code>Design&lt;/code>, &lt;code>inspiration&lt;/code>, &lt;code>Credits&lt;/code>, &lt;code>Notes&lt;/code>, &lt;code>Code&lt;/code>, et cetera.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Or, you could attempt to mash things up together, where your archived files are in the Johnny Decimal format subsumed under a PARA structure. (This is the way I&amp;rsquo;m leaning, but I&amp;rsquo;m not completely sure).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then again, if you want to go completely overboard, you could build a &lt;a href="https://zettelkasten.de/introduction/">Zettelkasten&lt;/a>. If you want to talk about overkill. That&amp;rsquo;s more of a note-taking method than a full out organizational system, though.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The thing is, you read enough productivity books and you can trace each &amp;ldquo;system&amp;rsquo;s&amp;rdquo; antecedents. The PARA system is highly influenced by David Allen&amp;rsquo;s GTD methodology (which assumes you have people you can delegate tasks to, which I have always found to be a key weakness of the methodology; not everyone is an executive, David).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And all systems have baked-in biases. Like GTD implies the ability to delegate. PARA implies the ability to pay for either a book or what looks to be a very expensive course (and obviously, one which many people get value from, and Appleton&amp;rsquo;s sketchnotes are really useful). Johnny Decimal assumes that you&amp;rsquo;re going to be able to remember all those numbers.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I&amp;rsquo;m still unsure how I want to organize my 30+ years of files, just that I need to pick something and &lt;em>just do it&lt;/em> when I&amp;rsquo;m not in the mood to knit or crochet while watching television or if I need to take a 10 minute break from looking at my non-functional in a very specific way bit of code at work.&lt;/p>
&lt;hr>
&lt;p>At any rate, what I&amp;rsquo;m aiming for ultimately is a space where I hit publish more often than not. A space where I&amp;rsquo;m comfortable posting incomplete thoughts. A space that &lt;em>I&lt;/em> find useful in the future. A space which reflects who I am, with all my interests and ideas splattered all over the (virtual) pages.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m really into the concept of the &lt;a href="https://indieweb.org/slow_web">slow web&lt;/a>, which is the bedrock on which all the above noodling rests. I&amp;rsquo;ve been joking to myself that this is a hand-crafted, artisanal website, but&amp;ndash;that actually &lt;em>is&lt;/em> the goal.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Messing Around</title><link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/messing-around/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 00:38:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/messing-around/</guid><description>&lt;p>So here I am, in the wee hours of the morning, having frittered away the last 7 hours of my life on a few &amp;ldquo;quick&amp;rdquo; updates to the site.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Except I kept thinking of new ways to do things or fixing errors with the style sheets to the point where, except for the general layout and the little cactus icon up there (which is going to be replaced soon, I swear), it&amp;rsquo;s basically a whole new theme.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I mean, it&amp;rsquo;s held together with duct tape and bubblegum at this point, but it &lt;em>works&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So I made a new &lt;code>theme.toml&lt;/code> file and claimed it as my own&amp;ndash;obviously, giving credit to the previous developers who worked on it within the file. It&amp;rsquo;s nowhere &lt;em>near&lt;/em> ready to publish and honestly? I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I want to. It&amp;rsquo;s missing a lot of the things that people look for: no search, no emoji support, no pagination between posts,&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> no analytics, and probably a bunch of other things as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Three of the four things on that list are coming (search, emoji support, and pagination) and I will not use analytics. I might put some parameters in for Fathom, because they do have a strong privacy policy, but I don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ll use them myself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And I added a couple of things that other folks probably don&amp;rsquo;t think or care about: a clear statement of what&amp;rsquo;s going on here with regards to privacy and an acknowledgment that I reside on the traditional lands of the Lenapehoking people.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Oh, and there&amp;rsquo;s now a full text RSS feed, praise Jesus and pass the mashed potatoes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The other thing I did today was spend $2,236 and change on getting my car&amp;rsquo;s 30,000 mile service and front and back brake repairs. We&amp;rsquo;re going on a short road trip next week and it needed to be done. The Blubaru is 5 years old and only has 28,000 miles on her&amp;ndash;I&amp;rsquo;m expecting to drive her for another 10 years, at least.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then I went to pick up a prescription (I have been to CVS 4 times in the last 2 weeks, because can they sync up the 4 things I pick up from them in person? no, no they cannot) which cost me the princely sum of $0.39. So that&amp;rsquo;s something, I guess.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also spent a few hours this afternoon&amp;ndash;while waiting to hear from the dealership about the car&amp;ndash;working on my mosaic knitting project. I can see the light at the end of the tunnel and if I apply myself, I may be able to finish before we head out of town&amp;ndash;which means I could potentially cast on for something else. Or get out one of my many WIPs. I guess we&amp;rsquo;ll see what I may be in the mood to bring along with me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Tomorrow is laundry and putting together a packing list and perhaps attempting to work my way through the rest of the to do list that I&amp;rsquo;ve been ignoring for a good chunk of the week (my weeks start on Monday).&lt;/p>
&lt;section class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
&lt;hr>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
&lt;p>The previous developer was apparently using jQuery for that. And only that. Let us not.&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/section></description></item><item><title>Coding and Thinking</title><link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/coding-and-thinking/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 22:15:34 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/coding-and-thinking/</guid><description>&lt;p>Did you know that I have not one, but two kanban boards? One for getting this site set up as I want it to be, and another for mothballing my old site.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>They both have a LOT of things on them. It&amp;rsquo;s gonna be a lot of work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But this evening, I knocked out a fair number of backend things I wanted to fix on this site, primarily with the CSS. I figured out what all the different files were doing, removed the parts that were irrelevant (goodbye stupid jquery menu on mobile), and did my various imports in a way that made sense for me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also replaced a few things with links to CDNs instead of hosting the entire content here&amp;ndash;that allows me to keep up to date with the most current version of things but it does add a vulnerability in case those CDNs go down. They&amp;rsquo;re mostly for things like some of the icons and the CSS frameword the original author chose to use. If the CDNs do go down, things will degrade gracefully until they come back up again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>On a completely different topic:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Folks on Twitter have been so kind and I wrote yesterday about the &lt;a href="https://peculiar.monster/posts/f-stands-for-fungible">reasons I&amp;rsquo;ve chosen to distance myself from fandom&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wanted to give an example of the sort of lifting of phrasing/ideas in such a way that it&amp;rsquo;s clear that my work was the inspiration&amp;ndash;I ran across this just last night:&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I wrote on August 1, 2020:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Martin made the decision to first mention her unprecedented accomplishment of winning the Best Novel three years in a row–-no one else of any race or gender has ever accomplished a Best Novel hat trick–-and then attempt to undermine it&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>And in the the essay I ran across yesterday, that author wrote:&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>Martin has also been criticized for disrespecting the award winners, mispronouncing names and undercutting accomplishments like N. K. Jemisin’s “hat trick” of three Hugo awards for best novel in as many years,&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s not a word for word lifting, but as far as I know, I am the person who first referred to Jemisin&amp;rsquo;s historic achievement as a &amp;ldquo;hat trick,&amp;rdquo; and I immedately followed it with Martin&amp;rsquo;s attempt to undermine it. (I included the content of his undermining attempt, too.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this piece, the author uses undercut before mentioning Jemisin&amp;rsquo;s achievement. I know that undercut &lt;strong>isn&amp;rsquo;t&lt;/strong> the same word, but it can be used interchangeably with undermine in this context.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not linking the essay in question because I don&amp;rsquo;t want to stir up trouble, but this is the sort of low-grade theft I&amp;rsquo;ve dealt with for the last decade. My essays are good enough to read and gain inspiration from, but not good enough to cite.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll also note that apart my words, the author did an excellent job both sourcing and citing their sources.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please think about why that may be.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the aftermath of my post, I was accused of posting for clout, for hating George, for using indecent language, for being jealous, fo being all sorts of things I just wasn&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You know why I posted it? I was angry. I was angry that someone with the stature of George R.R. Martin couldn&amp;rsquo;t be bothered to take the time to learn how to say people&amp;rsquo;s names, but took the time to figure out which hat he was going to wear for which segment and which action figures he was going to put on display. I was angry that he made the entire ceremony about how good the past was, with no acknowledgement that the past SUCKED for a lot of people and still SUCKS for them STILL. I was angry on behalf of my friends and colleagues who had turned on the ceremony excited to see their works celebrated and who instead THAT.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yeah, I swore. And yeah, I used a metaphor involving the sun. And yeeting people into it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And I happened to be the first person to post any sort of response online. Which is the only reason it got the audience that it did.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, imagine, how I felt afterwards, being accused of everything I wasn&amp;rsquo;t and also knowing that I couldn&amp;rsquo;t defend myself. It was like all those writing workshops all over again: I had to sit and take the abuse in silence. And I&amp;rsquo;ve been taking the abuse in (relative) silence for nearly two years now.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s just been a lot. And I&amp;rsquo;m probably going to be writing a lot about my trauma here&amp;ndash;not just with regards to fandom, but also about my childhood.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You&amp;rsquo;ve been forewarned.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>F Stands for Fungible</title><link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/f-stands-for-fungible/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 16:55:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/f-stands-for-fungible/</guid><description>&lt;p>I started the process of mothballing my old site last night.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was really hard to go through nearly 700 posts and unpublish them, leaving only the ones I&amp;rsquo;m planning on archiving on a static site.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Really, really hard. Also hard was seeing people respond on Twitter to my statement a few days ago that I was shutting the site down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been, personally, a terrible few years. I&amp;rsquo;ve lost my health, my career, and now I&amp;rsquo;m losing the vast majority of my social network. I am &lt;strong>gutted&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The ongoing harassment, silencing, and other kinds of abuse I&amp;rsquo;ve had to deal with over the nearly 10 years I&amp;rsquo;ve been publishing there&amp;ndash;it&amp;rsquo;s just too much. I think that if I hadn&amp;rsquo;t felt so alone during last year&amp;rsquo;s Hugo season and if people with larger platforms on social media had done &lt;strong>something&lt;/strong> to defend me instead of choosing to let me be the tank for people&amp;rsquo;s dissatisfaction with the Hugo ballot&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because that was a &lt;strong>choice&lt;/strong>. Let&amp;rsquo;s not pretend that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t. A lot of people knew how distressed I was by the bad faith arguments and the intimations that if I were a decent person, I&amp;rsquo;d have refused the nomination and they chose to say and do nothing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then when I was brigaded by a bunch of leftier-than-thou jackasses after the Hugos&amp;ndash;again, no support. The fiction finalists who received abuse did get a lot of support, but when I posted in the finalist Slack that I was also being abused and the only other person who responded was another fan, well. That showed me who the SFF community finds importand and who they don&amp;rsquo;t. Shortly after, I quietly peaced out of the Slack since I no longer felt welcome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I often joke that F doesn&amp;rsquo;t stand for fan, it stands for fungible.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>fungible&lt;/strong>: being something (such as money or a commodity) of such a nature that one part or quantity may be replaced by another equal part or quantity in paying a debt or settling an account&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That is, fans like myself are seen by many pro writers and SMOFs as interchangeable cogs in the SFF community. And since we are fungible, when someone&amp;rsquo;s pushed aside or leaves, well, it&amp;rsquo;s not a big deal. Someone else will certainly come along. And I am definitely feeling disposable. Surely, there will come along someone else to fill my particular niche in the SFF community. I wish them luck, because they&amp;rsquo;re going to need it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve talked a little bit about what I&amp;rsquo;ve had to deal with over the last ten years, let me make it explicit:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>professional writers I thought were friends not only expressing relief that my essay didn&amp;rsquo;t win a Hugo, but the fact that it was nominated was a disgrace and saying so in a place where I could not only see it, but interact with it&amp;ndash;and their silence when I expressed my disappointment that they hadn&amp;rsquo;t bothered to hide it from me
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the comments on said post, some of which called my nomination the worst thing ever to happen to the Hugos, &lt;strong>worse&lt;/strong> than that time Harlan Ellison grabbed Connie Willis&amp;rsquo;s breast at the Hugo Awards Ceremony (there is video, you can look it up)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>aforementioned brigading by a bunch of leftier-than-thou jackasses on Twitter
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the ringleaders have also made photoshopped memes of a post I deleted which they think is &lt;strong>hilarious&lt;/strong> (it&amp;rsquo;s not)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>one of them also published a &amp;ldquo;poem&amp;rdquo; which was &amp;ldquo;inspired&amp;rdquo; by my deleted tweet and which also included the image and the tweet&amp;rsquo;s text&lt;/li>
&lt;li>their creation of a &amp;ldquo;movement&amp;rdquo; in SFF that they can&amp;rsquo;t even define cogently which appears to have been created, in part, as a way to direct harassment towards me by getting the attention of professional writers with a significant platform&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ongoing defense of the subject of my essay, which is just weird because he&amp;rsquo;s a cis het white man with a swimming pool full of money: presumably everything they hate about capitalism and the power structures it sustains&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>having my work appropriated by professional non-fiction writers and not credited and when they were asked to credit me, made pathetic excuses&lt;/li>
&lt;li>endless accusations of whining, of jealousy, or of just wanting more traffic&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&amp;ldquo;friendly advice&amp;rdquo; to be less blunt, to be nicer, to be quiet&lt;/li>
&lt;li>abusive comments calling me names, making fun of my appearance, telling me to die and/or kill myself&lt;/li>
&lt;li>doxxed 3 times in 2 years by trolls, Worldcon, and SFWA&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Legitimate criticism and engaging with my arguments? I have no problem with that. It&amp;rsquo;s when all this other stuff happens and happens because I&amp;rsquo;m saying things that people don&amp;rsquo;t like or don&amp;rsquo;t want to hear or because I don&amp;rsquo;t look the way they think I should (pray tell, how &lt;strong>should&lt;/strong> I look?).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And it&amp;rsquo;s been ongoing for nearly 10 years and for the most part, the attacks are &lt;strong>coming from inside the house&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Is it any wonder that I feel like I need a little space to re-grow and to find my voice again?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean I&amp;rsquo;m not sad about walking away: I am. I know that there are many people that I will lose touch with, since I won&amp;rsquo;t be interacting with them on Twitter or seeing them at conventions. I know that when I do start attending conventions again, I won&amp;rsquo;t be asked to be on programming anymore&amp;ndash;and I love being on panels and I&amp;rsquo;ve been told that I&amp;rsquo;m good at being on panels.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Perhaps, eventually, I&amp;rsquo;ll feel comfortable shedding this pseudonym. For now, though, it&amp;rsquo;s exactly what I need.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Current Feelings Towards SFF Fandom</title><link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/sff-feelings-mood/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 13:25:06 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/sff-feelings-mood/</guid><description>&lt;p>&lt;img src="acnh-big-mood.png" alt="An Animal Crossing New Horizons character sitting in a cheap lawn chair in the evening with a tray table full of empty alcohol bottles next to them. In front of them is a burning oil barrel, two bags of trash, a can of gasoline, and a fire extinguisher. The character is wearing a red hat and a blue shirt that has a white cat on it shooting laser beam out of its eyes. The character&amp;rsquo;s eyes are half-closed, their mouth is open in dismay, and there are two bubble floating near their head. It&amp;rsquo;s evening.">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is a fairly accurate description of how I&amp;rsquo;m currently feeling about SFF fandom. Burn it all down, my children.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Random Thoughts (June 9)</title><link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/random-thoughts/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 09:52:04 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/random-thoughts/</guid><description>&lt;p>Oof. I went in for my monthly-ish paracentesis yesterday morning.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you don&amp;rsquo;t know what this is, here&amp;rsquo;s &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Paracentesis">a handy explainer from Wikipedia&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First of all, I was up entirely too early for my own good. But it did mean I was able to take my meds and eat breakfast before having to leave for the hospital, so that&amp;rsquo;s something, yes?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Normally, it&amp;rsquo;s not too bad, but the doctor doing them yesterday was a resident and while she was very nice and perfectly competent, she was also still a &lt;em>resident&lt;/em>, which means that she wasn&amp;rsquo;t as skilled as some of the doctors who have been there for years. And I&amp;rsquo;m a bit of a tough case&amp;ndash;I get tapped on my left side, not the right, and I&amp;rsquo;m not a high volume person anymore (thank God&amp;ndash;that&amp;rsquo;s 5L or more).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I got home, I took my pain meds and went directly to bed. I ended up spending most of the day in bed, which meant I didn&amp;rsquo;t get good sleep last night&amp;ndash;which means I was up at 4:30 am this morning for a few hours (I was able to see the day restart on Animal Crossing, which I&amp;rsquo;d never done before, so yay?) and then was able to get back to sleep for a couple of hours and then I was up for the day. And I&amp;rsquo;m still in a bit of pain. Boo.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My code editor&amp;ndash;Atom&amp;ndash;is being sunset at the end of the year, so I&amp;rsquo;m looking for alternatives. I&amp;rsquo;m leaning towards Sublime Text and Sublime Merge over VSCode, mainly because I feel like VSCode is bloated as all get out. It makes me cranky, though, because I &lt;em>finally&lt;/em> got a good workflow going in Atom and managed to learn a bunch of keyboard shortcuts and now I&amp;rsquo;m going to have to learn different ones. Meh.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Still haven&amp;rsquo;t had a chance to rework the colors here, but maybe this weekend? There&amp;rsquo;s a lot of weirdness in the CSS&amp;ndash;like the theme&amp;rsquo;s author made a &lt;em>separate&lt;/em> CSS file for each partial template and is importing them into the main CSS which is, just, weird.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is mostly a post to make a post. I&amp;rsquo;ve been thinking a lot about SFF fandom and how Certain Parties just seem so intent on stirring shit up with their ridiculous s&amp;mdash;-core concept, something which defines a &lt;em>negative&lt;/em> and not what they&amp;rsquo;re doing, which is a lot of body horror. I don&amp;rsquo;t think SFF necessarily needs more body horror, thanks.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Also, these people don&amp;rsquo;t actually seem to be very widely read in SFF and therefore think that no one is reading or writing &amp;ldquo;dark&amp;rdquo; fiction and well, that&amp;rsquo;s a crock of shit. And they&amp;rsquo;re &lt;em>very&lt;/em> intent on lionizing GRRM for some reason. I don&amp;rsquo;t know why.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyhow, I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing a lot of thinking about this whole thing for the past few months and I&amp;rsquo;m hoping, at some point, to be able to write something coherent about it as opposed to what I&amp;rsquo;ve just written.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And now? It&amp;rsquo;s time for me to get to work! Work! How glorious it is to be able to work at a job that I really enjoy and that I seem to be reasonably good at? I mean, still a newbie developer, but I&amp;rsquo;m learning and seem to be learning fast enough.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Better Colors?</title><link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/better-colors/</link><pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 23:21:11 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/better-colors/</guid><description>&lt;p>The spaghetti that is this site&amp;rsquo;s CSS is really something else&amp;ndash;to the point where using the override files just doesn&amp;rsquo;t work because there&amp;rsquo;s so much stuff squirreled away in different places and it all takes different precedence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve made a kanban board for the things I want to do and a bunch of them include &amp;ldquo;refactor and consolidate X, Y, or Z.&amp;rdquo; I suspect that when I&amp;rsquo;m done, it&amp;rsquo;ll be an entirely new template.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not thrilled with the colors and I think I need to rework them so there are more constrast colors and less four different shades of pinky-purple. But at least I managed to fix the damn fonts and hyphenation. The previous choices were&amp;ndash;choices. Yes. That&amp;rsquo;s the word.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I had a two hour nap with Miles this afternoon. He&amp;rsquo;s the only cat I&amp;rsquo;ve ever been able to nap with&amp;ndash;I can say to him, &amp;ldquo;Miles, want to come take a nap?&amp;rdquo; and he&amp;rsquo;ll get up from wherever he&amp;rsquo;s at (on a cat tree, in a sunbeam) to follow me into the bedroom and wait relatively patiently for me to get my glasses off and the white noise on and get into bed&amp;ndash;and then he&amp;rsquo;ll hop up and settle himself on my chest and we&amp;rsquo;ll both sleep and I&amp;rsquo;ll try to not suffocate in his fur.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>When I&amp;rsquo;m having a bad body day, he&amp;rsquo;ll often herd me to bed to take a nap. It&amp;rsquo;s like he &lt;em>knows&lt;/em> somehow.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This doesn&amp;rsquo;t work at night&amp;ndash;he sometimes sleeps at the foot of the bed at night, but he prefers other places to do his important cat business overnight.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>He&amp;rsquo;s a funny cat, but he&amp;rsquo;s my cat and I love him so much. He&amp;rsquo;s the very best black cat I&amp;rsquo;ve ever had. (I really can&amp;rsquo;t quantify which cat&amp;rsquo;s the best of the best, they&amp;rsquo;ve all been great in different ways&amp;ndash;all very different personalities.)&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Ridiculous Day</title><link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/ridiculous-day/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 22:02:49 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/ridiculous-day/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today&amp;rsquo;s been a day of a lot of ridiculous all over the board.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First off, the day started with therapy. Which wasn&amp;rsquo;t ridiculous, but it was 8:15 in the morning so there&amp;rsquo;s a certain degree of waaaah going on (every week, my appointment is at 8:15 am every week) just in general. Talked about EMDR a little bit to help me deal with my DESNOS/cPTSD (the &lt;em>name&lt;/em> of the thing is shifting: DESNOS is the name in the current edition of the DSM, cPTSD is what it&amp;rsquo;s generally known by these days). I&amp;rsquo;m really good at masking, so it&amp;rsquo;s often hard to tell when I&amp;rsquo;m losing my shit or really anxious orm, to be honest, even when I&amp;rsquo;m really depressed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After therapy, I had to scoot along to my appointment with the PA at the Infectious Disease practice that&amp;rsquo;s been following me since 2018. They&amp;rsquo;re all great and the doctor who initially treated me, I&amp;rsquo;m convinced is the one who helped turn the tide for me&amp;ndash;not just by treating the massive infection I had as a result of the necrosis happening in my abdomen, but by advocating for me with other hospital staff. Sadly, they&amp;rsquo;re going to be following me for likely the rest of my life: I had sepsis 3 times in the fourth quarter of 2020&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>, so I&amp;rsquo;m on prophylactic oral antibiotics and need regular check-ins with them to make sure everything&amp;rsquo;s still fine. I did graduate from every 3 months to every 6 months for appointments, though!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But see, I was sneaky and I took a little time before therapy and before my Infectious Disease appointment to mess around here; I decided last night that the theme I&amp;rsquo;d initially chosen was too complex both for my needs and for my level of ability, so I decided on Cactus as something a bit more streamlined if less flashy (I do like the color-changing cactus icon but I am going to replace it with something else). So I attempted to clone it in as a git submodule and I &lt;em>really&lt;/em> shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have done that&amp;ndash;I have terrible luck with the git submodule at work, I don&amp;rsquo;t know why I thought this was any different. Like I fucked things up so badly the site wouldn&amp;rsquo;t deploy and I had to go to &lt;a href="https://ohshitgit.com/">Oh Shit, Git!?!&lt;/a> to find what I needed to fix things.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But fix them I did and after I got home it was to work! In the spare room!&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The first thing I do every day is review the to do list I (hopefully) made the day before&amp;ndash;I only work 5-6 hours a day, so I have to make sure those hours count. By the time I got settled in and done with the list review, it was time for a meeting. The meeting ran short, so I started on my top task: pulling user IDs out of the beta database so we could award beta testers a special achievement in production. The PR for the achievement is still in queue to be deployed, but I wanted to have all the user IDs and usernames and email addresses in place.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;and it took me all fucking afternoon. Because our database is MongoDB, which is noSQL which means there are no relations between the different collections (they&amp;rsquo;re not even tables, they&amp;rsquo;re just JSON files, sob) and because the beta test involved testing group functionality and both parties and guilds fall under groups&amp;hellip;and while you can only be in one party, you can be in as many guilds as you want. I only had the email address of one person per guild and needed to be able to award the achievement to everyone in the group that participated. And I&amp;rsquo;m not great at queryng MongoDB because the operands and syntax are just so foreign to me after so many years of working with a terribly design SQL database. So it took me all fucking afternoon.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With an intermission where I checked on the status of my insulin prescription, which was supposed to be released from hold earlier this week and was not. I&amp;rsquo;ve been trying to get it filled for the better part of a week&amp;ndash;I was able to get all my other prescriptions transferred to my new insurance and filled with no problem, bu the insulin has been terrible.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, there was no response from my doctor&amp;rsquo;s office when CVS/caremark (OF COURSE IT&amp;rsquo;S THEM) contacted them for &lt;em>either&lt;/em> a new prescription &lt;em>or&lt;/em> a prior authorization&amp;ndash;nevermind that those are &lt;em>two completely different things&lt;/em>, why there&amp;rsquo;s the same message for both statuses on the customer end is beyond my understanding but most things on the CVS/caremark website are beyond my understanding. Like why is it so slow? Why do the apps suck so much?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyhow, I digress.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I had to contact my doctor&amp;rsquo;s office three times before someone got back to me&amp;ndash;I sent a message, which was never forwarded, I called and spoke to someone who claimed that I hadn&amp;rsquo;t sent a message and that they hadn&amp;rsquo;t received anything from CVS/caremark, and then I finally sent a third message which did make it through. And it turned out that a prior authorization was needed.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For a medication without which I will &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Diabetic_ketoacidosis">&lt;strong>&lt;em>DIE A TERRIBLE DEATH&lt;/em>&lt;/strong>&lt;/a>.&lt;sup id="fnref:3">&lt;a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">3&lt;/a>&lt;/sup>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I received a robo-call and then a form letter from my insurer informing me that they were going to allow me to continue to live by granting me a prior authoriztion for my insulin until I am 65, at which point I suppose I become Medicare&amp;rsquo;s problem. If there still is a Medicare in 2039.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So on Tuesday, I called to see about getting the prescription off hold and filled. The person I spoke to assured me that she had accomplished this.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One thing that CVS/caremark is good at is sending email. I got a number of emails informing me about all sorts of things over the last two days, but nothing about my insulin. So I decided to take a small break from work and check the status online. It was still on hold. I called. The prior authorization had not yet made its way through the system to the point where my prescription could be filled. The rep told me I needed a prior authorization and I told him that I would be happy to tell him the reference number on the letter I received from my insurer. He did a bit more checking and lo, there it was. And now it&amp;rsquo;s supposedly free to be filled and shipped to me next week.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Let us now take a moment to contemplate how this ridiculous system hurts people who can&amp;rsquo;t manage their insurer or CVS/caremark&amp;rsquo;s website either because they&amp;rsquo;re hard to use or because lack of internet access. How it hurts people who can&amp;rsquo;t make phone call after phone call to sort things out. How this hurts people who don&amp;rsquo;t know that they need to keep that piece of paper they got in the mail. How this hurts people with various kinds of disabilities who have to rely on their caregivers to navigate this system on their behalf. On all sorts of people, really. I am &lt;em>lucky&lt;/em> that I am able to go Full Karen if needed to get this shit taken care of&amp;ndash;not everyone can. And not everyone is as persistent or as stubborn as I am.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My stubbornness has served me well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And after that delightful intermission, I went back to work. I finally got the data completed so we will be able to grant folks their achievement when it goes live and then I decided it would be fun to work on this site.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>There&amp;rsquo;s still a lot I want to do to move things around to my liking&amp;ndash;the icon, the colors, the font and spacing&amp;ndash;but the structure of this theme is significantly more simple than the other one and I was even able to leave a helpful comment on one of the issues on GitHub about the tags page. Even though it looks like the developer has abandoned the project&amp;ndash;there are two open PRs to fix the same problem, but neither of them actually fix it!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But you know, it keeps me out of trouble. And only scares me a little bit, that I might be turning into my father, who spent most of my childhood and well into my adulthood sitting in front of a computer, coding. (In other words, I come by this naturally. Or something.)&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Things I want to do, in no particular order:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>New image in the header&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Previous/Next links on individual pages&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Post wordcount because why not?&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Removing the &amp;ldquo;Home&amp;rdquo; menu link on the home page, golly that drives me up a wall&lt;/li>
&lt;li>New font and colors
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>Get rid of the embedded font files, who does that in the year of our Lord 2022 just find a nice Google font and let it goooooo&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Emoji support&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Stripping out all the code I don&amp;rsquo;t want to use, like the comments and the jquery and the analytics&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Combining desktop and mobile page navigation into one file&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Killing the image gallery deader than a doornail&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Looking into adding support for &lt;a href="https://indieweb.org/">IndieWeb&lt;/a> stuff!&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>And here&amp;rsquo;s your reward: a picture of the first roses of the season. This a polyanthus variety called &amp;ldquo;The Fairy,&amp;rdquo; the blooms are only about 1&amp;quot; in diameter and there are loads of them. They don&amp;rsquo;t smell, though, and they&amp;rsquo;re prickly as all get out. I love them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="20220602-first-roses.jpeg" alt="First Roses of the Year">&lt;/p>
&lt;section class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
&lt;hr>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
&lt;p>I was hospitalized for a week and was sent home with a PICC line for at-home IV antibiotics each time, which required time to administer and a weekly visit from a nurse to change the dressing. Before I had this series of hospitalizations, I was&amp;ndash;according to my former manager&amp;ndash;on track to achieve my goals for 2020. Afterwards, though, she characterized me in my annual review as &amp;ldquo;unreliable&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;inconsistent.&amp;rdquo; Hmmmmm.&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:2" role="doc-endnote">
&lt;p>I actually have a very nice WFH set up, thank you salary from OldJob, you&amp;rsquo;re about the only thing I miss.&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:3" role="doc-endnote">
&lt;p>Huh. Apparently the way the scientists were first able to extract and purify insulin for use in people was &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Insulin#Extraction_and_purification">by giving dogs what amounted to surgically induced pancreatic necrosis&lt;/a>. Those poor dogs.&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:3" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/section></description></item><item><title>Trying to Post Images</title><link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/image-posting/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 11:18:02 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/image-posting/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m trying to figure out how to manage images; I don&amp;rsquo;t really want to do &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io/content-management/page-bundles/">page bundles&lt;/a>&amp;hellip;but I guess I am for now. Meh.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Annnnd, of course, I can&amp;rsquo;t get any of the theme&amp;rsquo;s built-in image shortcodes to actually &lt;em>respect&lt;/em> my settings&amp;ndash;do I want my images linked? No, no I do not. And why the FUCK is it not rendering the CSS that at least hides my link formatting? I have it in the right order, it&amp;rsquo;s just straight-up &lt;em>ignoring&lt;/em> me. I&amp;rsquo;m starting to think I need to find another, simpler theme to work with. This one is awfully finicky and NOT GOOD at respecting my choices. Which is why I wanted to get away from the WordPress ecosystem in the first place: to have better choices.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Anyhow. Enjoy this image of my African violet blooming&amp;ndash;I&amp;rsquo;ve never had one bloom before, and I&amp;rsquo;ve even managed to keep it alive for over a year. That&amp;rsquo;s a victory, for sure. The second image is of my current knitting project, &lt;a href="https://www.ravelry.com/patterns/library/mutual-admiration-society">Mutual Admiration Society&lt;/a> (Rav link, sorry), which I bought as a kit eons ago. It uses a technique new to me, mosaic knitting, which is slipping stitches on every row with two alternating colors. It looks a lot harder than it actually is. The gray speckled yarn is Miss Babs&amp;rsquo;s Yowza and it is incredible to work with&amp;ndash;I would love to make a sweater with this stuff, it&amp;rsquo;s so round and bouncy and nice to work with.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="20220531-african-violet.jpeg" alt="This is an African Violet.">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="20220531-mosaic-knitting.jpeg" alt="This is mosaic knitting.">&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Code, Why Are You Like This?</title><link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/code-why-are-you-like-this/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 11:35:21 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/code-why-are-you-like-this/</guid><description>&lt;p>And of course, no sooner than I finished my previous post and decided to deploy the site than I ran into a bunch of problems, some bigger than others.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First, I had to set the DNS record to point at GitHub Pages. And that takes time to propogate and I am &lt;em>impatient&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The DNS wasn&amp;rsquo;t propogating and GH was tellng me that I&amp;rsquo;d configured something wrong, so it recommended that I set &lt;code>A&lt;/code> records to point at the GitHub Pages IP addresses&amp;hellip;except it didn&amp;rsquo;t actually link to where I could &lt;em>find&lt;/em> those IP addresses.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I finally found them buried in GH&amp;rsquo;s documentation, but I&amp;rsquo;ll be damned if I can find the page again, even with searching through my browser history.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also set up the &lt;code>CNAME&lt;/code> record at the same time.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then I had to set up the GitHub workflow to actually deploy from my repo to the page&amp;ndash;and unbeknownst to me, there was a &lt;em>critical&lt;/em> piece of missing information from the workflow as written.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And that piece of information was setting &lt;code>cname: peculiar.monster&lt;/code> in the deploy script.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Seriously. &lt;code>CNAME&lt;/code> kept on disappearing from the &lt;code>gh-pages&lt;/code> branch and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out why until I looked at &lt;a href="https://github.com/marketplace/actions/github-pages-action#%EF%B8%8F-add-cname-file-cname">this GH Action&lt;/a> which mentioned setting &lt;code>CNAME&lt;/code>, while &lt;a href="https://github.com/marketplace/actions/hugo-setup">the Hugo-specific action&lt;/a>&amp;ndash;the one I chose to use&amp;ndash;did not mention it anywhere. No wonder it was being removed!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So, with that sorted, I turned my attention to why either the theme or Hugo wasn&amp;rsquo;t respecting my `&lt;/p>
&lt;p>` tag. Turned out that &lt;em>Hugo&lt;/em> was respecting it just fine and the theme absolutely was not&amp;ndash;and of course, this isn&amp;rsquo;t actually documented &lt;em>in&lt;/em> the theme.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After digging through the CSS, I figured out where the problem was, it was in a bit of code from &lt;code>themes/LoveIt/assets/css/_page/_home.scss&lt;/code>:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#282a36;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-scss" data-lang="scss">&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f"> 1&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#50fa7b">.home&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">[&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">data-home&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">=&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">posts&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">]&lt;/span> {
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f"> 2&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#50fa7b">.summary&lt;/span> {
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f"> 3&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#50fa7b">.content&lt;/span> {
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f"> 4&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">@include&lt;/span> box(vertical);
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f"> 5&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#50fa7b">-webkit-line-clamp&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">:&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#bd93f9">3&lt;/span>;
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f"> 6&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#50fa7b">margin-top&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">:&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#bd93f9">.3&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#8be9fd">rem&lt;/span>;
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f"> 7&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#50fa7b">width&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">:&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#bd93f9">100&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#8be9fd">%&lt;/span>;
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f"> 8&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#50fa7b">overflow&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">:&lt;/span> hidden;
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f"> 9&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#50fa7b">text-overflow&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">:&lt;/span> ellipsis;
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">10&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">@include&lt;/span> overflow-wrap(break-word);
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">11&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#50fa7b">color&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">:&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#8be9fd;font-style:italic">$global-font-secondary-color&lt;/span>;
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">12&lt;/span> }
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">13&lt;/span> }
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">14&lt;/span>}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>I did delete the classes that weren&amp;rsquo;t relevant to the problem at hand&amp;ndash;the &lt;code>home[data-home=posts]&lt;/code> class has a &lt;em>lot&lt;/em> going on, more than is relevant to explain the current problem.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A bit of research, however, quickly helped me to figure out that &lt;code>-webkit-line-clamp: 3;&lt;/code> was the culprit. It was restricting the summary display to three lines, it was a class I am not familiar with, and I wasn&amp;rsquo;t sure what the options were.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Now, how to fix it?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am not a methodical sort of person, alas&amp;ndash;and looking at the code condensed like I did above actually helped me to get to a solution&amp;ndash;but my normal way of doing things is to just throw lines of code at the problem and see if anything sticks. This is a terrible habit that I&amp;rsquo;m trying to break&amp;ndash;it was fine when coding was something I did occasionally and for fun, but it&amp;rsquo;s not great when I&amp;rsquo;m trying to write code at work.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And here&amp;rsquo;s the answer, to the LoveIt theme disrespecting summary length and the &lt;code>&amp;lt;!--more--&amp;gt;&lt;/code> tag, placed within &lt;code>assets/css/_custom.scss&lt;/code>. :sweat_smile:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#282a36;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-scss" data-lang="scss">&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">1&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#50fa7b">.home&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">[&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">data-home&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">=&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">posts&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">]&lt;/span> {
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">2&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#50fa7b">.summary&lt;/span> {
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">3&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#50fa7b">.content&lt;/span> {
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">4&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#50fa7b">-webkit-line-clamp&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">:&lt;/span> none;
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">5&lt;/span> }
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">6&lt;/span> }
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">7&lt;/span>}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>Then there was the problem with the paragraphs not being properly separated and the spacing just being weird. That was easy to solve, just a few more lines:&lt;/p>
&lt;div class="highlight">&lt;pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#282a36;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4">&lt;code class="language-scss" data-lang="scss">&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">1&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#50fa7b">.home&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">[&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">data-home&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">=&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">posts&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">]&lt;/span> {
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">2&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#50fa7b">.summary&lt;/span> {
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">3&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#50fa7b">.content&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">p&lt;/span> {
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">4&lt;/span> &lt;span style="color:#50fa7b">display&lt;/span>&lt;span style="color:#ff79c6">:&lt;/span> block;
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">5&lt;/span> }
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">6&lt;/span> }
&lt;span style="margin-right:0.4em;padding:0 0.4em 0 0.4em;color:#7f7f7f">7&lt;/span>}
&lt;/code>&lt;/pre>&lt;/div>&lt;p>And there, everything is so much more to my liking. :tada:&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hello World</title><link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 20:06:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/hello-world/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hello world!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While this is a new site, I am not new to blogging. I&amp;rsquo;ve been blogging one way or another since 1999, give or take. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a lot of different sites over the years&amp;ndash;from Diaryland to Greymatter to Movable Type to LiveJournal to WordPress and now I&amp;rsquo;m using &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io">Hugo&lt;/a> because, to be quite honest, I am unhappy with the direction WordPress has taken their product&amp;ndash;they seem to assume that everyone wants to sell something and too often what&amp;rsquo;s for sale is a piece of someone&amp;rsquo;s soul.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have no desire to make this site generate any sort of regular source of income or to leverage it into something bigger than what it is. I&amp;rsquo;m not looking for visibility or followers or to become any sort of influencer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m looking for a place to document my life and how I&amp;rsquo;m living it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I &lt;em>miss&lt;/em> writing for its own sake. There are so many things I want to write about and haven&amp;rsquo;t felt as if I can, in part because technology is getting in my way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>WordPress is an unwieldy beast and every time I log on, there&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>something&lt;/em> that needs updating. I hate that things I&amp;rsquo;d consider to be part of the core functionality of a CMS isn&amp;rsquo;t there and there&amp;rsquo;s a whole ecosystem of people making their living selling that core functionality to you&amp;ndash;and if they run on a freemium model, the plugins call home, which is a significant privacy and security concern.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am planning to mothball my old site and unpublishing nearly all the posts; what I&amp;rsquo;m planning on leaving behind will be converted to static site, probably using &lt;a href="https://www.11ty.dev/">11ty&lt;/a>, because playing with frameworks is fun and their name makes me laugh.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Like many others, I have become increasingly disillusioned with the algorithmic web and with the centering of search engine optimization and selling when it comes to publishing online.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example: Twitter doesn&amp;rsquo;t show me the tweets I&amp;rsquo;m interested in, instead it shows me what will make me angry or despairing. Facebook lets me know know which of my friends and family are not-so-secret bigots (I&amp;rsquo;d&amp;rsquo;ve deleted that by now except FB Messenger is the main way I talk to my sister and dad). Instagram seems to exist in order to make me feel bad about myself or to tempt me into buying things I really don&amp;rsquo;t need. None of this is good for my mental health.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was &lt;a href="https://institute.global/policy/social-media-futures-what-brigading">brigaded on Twitter&lt;/a> earlier this year for a casual, off-hand remark I made to some friends after the Hugo Awards ceremony and the ringleaders harassed me for &lt;em>months&lt;/em> for no reason other that they &lt;em>could&lt;/em>. And because I was not someone that the wider SFF community perceived as important, I was more or less left to deal with it alone. (Those of you who did support me, you have my :purple_heart: forever. The rest of you? :fu: )&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So this is an attempt to get back to basics&amp;ndash;to write a few times a week about how I&amp;rsquo;m feeling (current status: ow my pancreas), about what I&amp;rsquo;m reading, and whatever else I want. And most importantly: to work at becoming a &lt;em>better&lt;/em> writer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I want to get away from the corporatized and capitalism-focused web and back to what attracted me to the internet in the first place: finding interesting people and reading what they have to say.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not planning on glossing over any of my health issues, but I&amp;rsquo;m not going to wallow in them or present myself as some sort of heroine fighting a battle with her body: my goal is to make peace with this body, as it&amp;rsquo;s the only one I get to have. And if I have to use assistive devices and medications in order to keep going, then that&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m going to do. And I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about it&amp;ndash;there are so few of us who have survived necrotizing pancreatitis writing honestly about what it&amp;rsquo;s like that I feel I owe it to my past self to do so.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But my disability isn&amp;rsquo;t all of who I am: I am also a voracious reader and I make things with yarn. I&amp;rsquo;m also a JavaScript developer and I work for a really neat little company and it&amp;rsquo;s so &lt;em>good&lt;/em>, especially when compared with my prior job, which was actively making my health worse through an abusive manager who knew how to use the corporate bureaucracy to her benefit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think most of you reading this have noticed that I&amp;rsquo;m not using any part of my legal name on this site, although it is not difficult to discover. I am asking that this deliberate omission be respected as much as possible. I&amp;rsquo;m respecting your privacy by not using any cookies or other tracking technologies, so please respect mine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally: welcome, world. I&amp;rsquo;m glad you&amp;rsquo;re here for this journey. Let&amp;rsquo;s have some fun.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>