<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Peculiar Monster</title>
    <link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Peculiar Monster</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://peculiar.monster/logo.png</url>
      <link>https://peculiar.monster/logo.png</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 20:11:49 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://peculiar.monster/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Coding, Work, and Random Updates</title>
      <link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/coding-work-random-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jul 2022 20:11:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/coding-work-random-updates/</guid>
      <description>Me: Oh, let me change the theme, it won&amp;rsquo;t that big of a deal.
time passes
Me: Six hours isn&amp;rsquo;t bad, right?
 So, yes: I did change a few colors. And the font, and the entire theme. And I made a colophon page and managed to actually code it in properly. Which is pretty exciting, not gonna lie.
Anyhow. I&amp;rsquo;m sure some things look funky and I didn&amp;rsquo;t notice.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Links of Note, July 2022</title>
      <link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/links-of-note-july-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jul 2022 16:07:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/links-of-note-july-2022/</guid>
      <description>a short collection of links I&amp;#39;ve found interesting</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Art of Losing</title>
      <link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/the-art-of-losing/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jul 2022 11:12:46 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/the-art-of-losing/</guid>
      <description>The art of losing isn’t hard to master;
so many things seem filled with the intent
to be lost that their loss is no disaster.
 Four years ago today, I almost died.
And while I didn&amp;rsquo;t lose my life, I have had to master the art of losing nonetheless.
First The first thing I lost was my health. I&amp;rsquo;d been almost rudely healthy up to that point. I&amp;rsquo;d never been seriously sick beyond a couple of bouts of flu in my 20&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This Meatsuit is Annoying</title>
      <link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/this-meatsuit-is-annoying/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 16:04:19 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/this-meatsuit-is-annoying/</guid>
      <description>I am just not feeling the thing this week.
I had a mere 2.5L drained last week1 and you&amp;rsquo;d think that would have helped and&amp;ndash;nope.
I feel bloated and I basically haven&amp;rsquo;t felt hungry so there&amp;rsquo;s been a lot of forcing myself to eat and then I feel like I overate and it&amp;rsquo;s just not pleasant.
And I&amp;rsquo;m having weird random pain in my gut, but not enough to actually call my doctor or go to the ER about.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>It&#39;s Been Busy Around Here</title>
      <link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/its-been-busy-around-here/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jul 2022 12:02:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/its-been-busy-around-here/</guid>
      <description>It has been a week here.
I have:
 successfully wrangled custom radio button hover and focus states  the html radio buttons were offset from the custom ones and moving them helped the hover happen in the right places I am still mad at whoever originally coded the component, though   got a chunk of coding done for the mobile version of the site footer  the desktop version is good to go, but I have a few more bootstrap/flexbox things to figure out   helped a user regain access to their account using nothing more than an old photograph of their phone&amp;rsquo;s screen and a vague list of tasks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The land that never has been yet—</title>
      <link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/the-land-that-never-has-been-yet/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Jul 2022 16:48:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/the-land-that-never-has-been-yet/</guid>
      <description>Langston Hughes said it better than I can, especially for this 4th of July, one where we&amp;rsquo;re reeling from the endgame of a culture war that started before I was born.
 Let America Be America Again Let America be America again.
Let it be the dream it used to be.
Let it be the pioneer on the plain
Seeking a home where he himself is free.
(America never was America to me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thoughts on Digital Gardening and Information Organization</title>
      <link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/thoughts-on-digital-gardening-and-information-organization/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jul 2022 16:40:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/thoughts-on-digital-gardening-and-information-organization/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been spending a lot of time over the last week falling into various rabbit holes. So many.
But one thing I keep coming back to is how, on my previous blog, I felt paralyzed by the weight of perfection. As if I were under so much scrutiny that the smallest mistake would cause a shitstorm.
This feeling was only exacerbated by the fact that when I did say something stupid on Twitter, a group of leftier than thou folks who enjoy brigading other people for the tiniest of ideological differences decided to brigade me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Messing Around</title>
      <link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/messing-around/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jun 2022 00:38:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/messing-around/</guid>
      <description>So here I am, in the wee hours of the morning, having frittered away the last 7 hours of my life on a few &amp;ldquo;quick&amp;rdquo; updates to the site.
Except I kept thinking of new ways to do things or fixing errors with the style sheets to the point where, except for the general layout and the little cactus icon up there (which is going to be replaced soon, I swear), it&amp;rsquo;s basically a whole new theme.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coding and Thinking</title>
      <link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/coding-and-thinking/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 22:15:34 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/coding-and-thinking/</guid>
      <description>Did you know that I have not one, but two kanban boards? One for getting this site set up as I want it to be, and another for mothballing my old site.
They both have a LOT of things on them. It&amp;rsquo;s gonna be a lot of work.
But this evening, I knocked out a fair number of backend things I wanted to fix on this site, primarily with the CSS.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>F Stands for Fungible</title>
      <link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/f-stands-for-fungible/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 16:55:10 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/f-stands-for-fungible/</guid>
      <description>I started the process of mothballing my old site last night.
It was really hard to go through nearly 700 posts and unpublish them, leaving only the ones I&amp;rsquo;m planning on archiving on a static site.
Really, really hard. Also hard was seeing people respond on Twitter to my statement a few days ago that I was shutting the site down.
It&amp;rsquo;s been, personally, a terrible few years. I&amp;rsquo;ve lost my health, my career, and now I&amp;rsquo;m losing the vast majority of my social network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Current Feelings Towards SFF Fandom</title>
      <link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/sff-feelings-mood/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 13:25:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/sff-feelings-mood/</guid>
      <description>This is a fairly accurate description of how I&amp;rsquo;m currently feeling about SFF fandom. Burn it all down, my children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Random Thoughts (June 9)</title>
      <link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/random-thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 09:52:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/random-thoughts/</guid>
      <description>Oof. I went in for my monthly-ish paracentesis yesterday morning.
If you don&amp;rsquo;t know what this is, here&amp;rsquo;s a handy explainer from Wikipedia.
First of all, I was up entirely too early for my own good. But it did mean I was able to take my meds and eat breakfast before having to leave for the hospital, so that&amp;rsquo;s something, yes?
Normally, it&amp;rsquo;s not too bad, but the doctor doing them yesterday was a resident and while she was very nice and perfectly competent, she was also still a resident, which means that she wasn&amp;rsquo;t as skilled as some of the doctors who have been there for years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Better Colors?</title>
      <link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/better-colors/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jun 2022 23:21:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/better-colors/</guid>
      <description>The spaghetti that is this site&amp;rsquo;s CSS is really something else&amp;ndash;to the point where using the override files just doesn&amp;rsquo;t work because there&amp;rsquo;s so much stuff squirreled away in different places and it all takes different precedence.
I&amp;rsquo;ve made a kanban board for the things I want to do and a bunch of them include &amp;ldquo;refactor and consolidate X, Y, or Z.&amp;rdquo; I suspect that when I&amp;rsquo;m done, it&amp;rsquo;ll be an entirely new template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Ridiculous Day</title>
      <link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/ridiculous-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jun 2022 22:02:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/ridiculous-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today&amp;rsquo;s been a day of a lot of ridiculous all over the board.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trying to Post Images</title>
      <link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/image-posting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 11:18:02 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/image-posting/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m trying to figure out how to manage images; I don&amp;rsquo;t really want to do page bundles&amp;hellip;but I guess I am for now. Meh.
Annnnd, of course, I can&amp;rsquo;t get any of the theme&amp;rsquo;s built-in image shortcodes to actually respect my settings&amp;ndash;do I want my images linked? No, no I do not. And why the FUCK is it not rendering the CSS that at least hides my link formatting? I have it in the right order, it&amp;rsquo;s just straight-up ignoring me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code, Why Are You Like This?</title>
      <link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/code-why-are-you-like-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 May 2022 11:35:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/code-why-are-you-like-this/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;And of course, no sooner than I finished my previous post and decided to deploy the site than I ran into a bunch of problems, some bigger than others.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, I had to set the DNS record to point at GitHub Pages. And that takes time to propogate and I am &lt;em&gt;impatient&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The DNS wasn&amp;rsquo;t propogating and GH was tellng me that I&amp;rsquo;d configured something wrong, so it recommended that I set &lt;code&gt;A&lt;/code&gt; records to point at the GitHub Pages IP addresses&amp;hellip;except it didn&amp;rsquo;t actually link to where I could &lt;em&gt;find&lt;/em&gt; those IP addresses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I finally found them buried in GH&amp;rsquo;s documentation, but I&amp;rsquo;ll be damned if I can find the page again, even with searching through my browser history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also set up the &lt;code&gt;CNAME&lt;/code&gt; record at the same time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I had to set up the GitHub workflow to actually deploy from my repo to the page&amp;ndash;and unbeknownst to me, there was a &lt;em&gt;critical&lt;/em&gt; piece of missing information from the workflow as written.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And that piece of information was setting &lt;code&gt;cname: peculiar.monster&lt;/code&gt; in the deploy script.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Seriously. &lt;code&gt;CNAME&lt;/code&gt; kept on disappearing from the &lt;code&gt;gh-pages&lt;/code&gt; branch and I couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out why until I looked at &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/marketplace/actions/github-pages-action#%EF%B8%8F-add-cname-file-cname&#34;&gt;this GH Action&lt;/a&gt; which mentioned setting &lt;code&gt;CNAME&lt;/code&gt;, while &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/marketplace/actions/hugo-setup&#34;&gt;the Hugo-specific action&lt;/a&gt;&amp;ndash;the one I chose to use&amp;ndash;did not mention it anywhere. No wonder it was being removed!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, with that sorted, I turned my attention to why either the theme or Hugo wasn&amp;rsquo;t respecting my `&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 20:06:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Hello world!
While this is a new site, I am not new to blogging. I&amp;rsquo;ve been blogging one way or another since 1999, give or take. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a lot of different sites over the years&amp;ndash;from Diaryland to Greymatter to Movable Type to LiveJournal to WordPress and now I&amp;rsquo;m using Hugo because, to be quite honest, I am unhappy with the direction WordPress has taken their product&amp;ndash;they seem to assume that everyone wants to sell something and too often what&amp;rsquo;s for sale is a piece of someone&amp;rsquo;s soul.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
