<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>personal on Peculiar Monster</title><link>https://peculiar.monster/tags/personal/</link><description>Recent content in personal on Peculiar Monster</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>GigaMeow</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 16:55:10 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://peculiar.monster/tags/personal/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>F Stands for Fungible</title><link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/f-stands-for-fungible/</link><pubDate>Sat, 11 Jun 2022 16:55:10 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/f-stands-for-fungible/</guid><description>&lt;p>I started the process of mothballing my old site last night.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It was really hard to go through nearly 700 posts and unpublish them, leaving only the ones I&amp;rsquo;m planning on archiving on a static site.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Really, really hard. Also hard was seeing people respond on Twitter to my statement a few days ago that I was shutting the site down.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s been, personally, a terrible few years. I&amp;rsquo;ve lost my health, my career, and now I&amp;rsquo;m losing the vast majority of my social network. I am &lt;strong>gutted&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The ongoing harassment, silencing, and other kinds of abuse I&amp;rsquo;ve had to deal with over the nearly 10 years I&amp;rsquo;ve been publishing there&amp;ndash;it&amp;rsquo;s just too much. I think that if I hadn&amp;rsquo;t felt so alone during last year&amp;rsquo;s Hugo season and if people with larger platforms on social media had done &lt;strong>something&lt;/strong> to defend me instead of choosing to let me be the tank for people&amp;rsquo;s dissatisfaction with the Hugo ballot&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Because that was a &lt;strong>choice&lt;/strong>. Let&amp;rsquo;s not pretend that it wasn&amp;rsquo;t. A lot of people knew how distressed I was by the bad faith arguments and the intimations that if I were a decent person, I&amp;rsquo;d have refused the nomination and they chose to say and do nothing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And then when I was brigaded by a bunch of leftier-than-thou jackasses after the Hugos&amp;ndash;again, no support. The fiction finalists who received abuse did get a lot of support, but when I posted in the finalist Slack that I was also being abused and the only other person who responded was another fan, well. That showed me who the SFF community finds importand and who they don&amp;rsquo;t. Shortly after, I quietly peaced out of the Slack since I no longer felt welcome.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I often joke that F doesn&amp;rsquo;t stand for fan, it stands for fungible.&lt;/p>
&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>fungible&lt;/strong>: being something (such as money or a commodity) of such a nature that one part or quantity may be replaced by another equal part or quantity in paying a debt or settling an account&lt;/p>
&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;p>That is, fans like myself are seen by many pro writers and SMOFs as interchangeable cogs in the SFF community. And since we are fungible, when someone&amp;rsquo;s pushed aside or leaves, well, it&amp;rsquo;s not a big deal. Someone else will certainly come along. And I am definitely feeling disposable. Surely, there will come along someone else to fill my particular niche in the SFF community. I wish them luck, because they&amp;rsquo;re going to need it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve talked a little bit about what I&amp;rsquo;ve had to deal with over the last ten years, let me make it explicit:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>professional writers I thought were friends not only expressing relief that my essay didn&amp;rsquo;t win a Hugo, but the fact that it was nominated was a disgrace and saying so in a place where I could not only see it, but interact with it&amp;ndash;and their silence when I expressed my disappointment that they hadn&amp;rsquo;t bothered to hide it from me
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the comments on said post, some of which called my nomination the worst thing ever to happen to the Hugos, &lt;strong>worse&lt;/strong> than that time Harlan Ellison grabbed Connie Willis&amp;rsquo;s breast at the Hugo Awards Ceremony (there is video, you can look it up)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>aforementioned brigading by a bunch of leftier-than-thou jackasses on Twitter
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>the ringleaders have also made photoshopped memes of a post I deleted which they think is &lt;strong>hilarious&lt;/strong> (it&amp;rsquo;s not)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>one of them also published a &amp;ldquo;poem&amp;rdquo; which was &amp;ldquo;inspired&amp;rdquo; by my deleted tweet and which also included the image and the tweet&amp;rsquo;s text&lt;/li>
&lt;li>their creation of a &amp;ldquo;movement&amp;rdquo; in SFF that they can&amp;rsquo;t even define cogently which appears to have been created, in part, as a way to direct harassment towards me by getting the attention of professional writers with a significant platform&lt;/li>
&lt;li>ongoing defense of the subject of my essay, which is just weird because he&amp;rsquo;s a cis het white man with a swimming pool full of money: presumably everything they hate about capitalism and the power structures it sustains&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>having my work appropriated by professional non-fiction writers and not credited and when they were asked to credit me, made pathetic excuses&lt;/li>
&lt;li>endless accusations of whining, of jealousy, or of just wanting more traffic&lt;/li>
&lt;li>&amp;ldquo;friendly advice&amp;rdquo; to be less blunt, to be nicer, to be quiet&lt;/li>
&lt;li>abusive comments calling me names, making fun of my appearance, telling me to die and/or kill myself&lt;/li>
&lt;li>doxxed 3 times in 2 years by trolls, Worldcon, and SFWA&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>Legitimate criticism and engaging with my arguments? I have no problem with that. It&amp;rsquo;s when all this other stuff happens and happens because I&amp;rsquo;m saying things that people don&amp;rsquo;t like or don&amp;rsquo;t want to hear or because I don&amp;rsquo;t look the way they think I should (pray tell, how &lt;strong>should&lt;/strong> I look?).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And it&amp;rsquo;s been ongoing for nearly 10 years and for the most part, the attacks are &lt;strong>coming from inside the house&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Is it any wonder that I feel like I need a little space to re-grow and to find my voice again?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>That doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean I&amp;rsquo;m not sad about walking away: I am. I know that there are many people that I will lose touch with, since I won&amp;rsquo;t be interacting with them on Twitter or seeing them at conventions. I know that when I do start attending conventions again, I won&amp;rsquo;t be asked to be on programming anymore&amp;ndash;and I love being on panels and I&amp;rsquo;ve been told that I&amp;rsquo;m good at being on panels.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Perhaps, eventually, I&amp;rsquo;ll feel comfortable shedding this pseudonym. For now, though, it&amp;rsquo;s exactly what I need.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Hello World</title><link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/hello-world/</link><pubDate>Sun, 29 May 2022 20:06:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/hello-world/</guid><description>&lt;p>Hello world!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>While this is a new site, I am not new to blogging. I&amp;rsquo;ve been blogging one way or another since 1999, give or take. I&amp;rsquo;ve had a lot of different sites over the years&amp;ndash;from Diaryland to Greymatter to Movable Type to LiveJournal to WordPress and now I&amp;rsquo;m using &lt;a href="https://gohugo.io">Hugo&lt;/a> because, to be quite honest, I am unhappy with the direction WordPress has taken their product&amp;ndash;they seem to assume that everyone wants to sell something and too often what&amp;rsquo;s for sale is a piece of someone&amp;rsquo;s soul.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I have no desire to make this site generate any sort of regular source of income or to leverage it into something bigger than what it is. I&amp;rsquo;m not looking for visibility or followers or to become any sort of influencer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m looking for a place to document my life and how I&amp;rsquo;m living it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I &lt;em>miss&lt;/em> writing for its own sake. There are so many things I want to write about and haven&amp;rsquo;t felt as if I can, in part because technology is getting in my way.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>WordPress is an unwieldy beast and every time I log on, there&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em>something&lt;/em> that needs updating. I hate that things I&amp;rsquo;d consider to be part of the core functionality of a CMS isn&amp;rsquo;t there and there&amp;rsquo;s a whole ecosystem of people making their living selling that core functionality to you&amp;ndash;and if they run on a freemium model, the plugins call home, which is a significant privacy and security concern.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I am planning to mothball my old site and unpublishing nearly all the posts; what I&amp;rsquo;m planning on leaving behind will be converted to static site, probably using &lt;a href="https://www.11ty.dev/">11ty&lt;/a>, because playing with frameworks is fun and their name makes me laugh.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Like many others, I have become increasingly disillusioned with the algorithmic web and with the centering of search engine optimization and selling when it comes to publishing online.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For example: Twitter doesn&amp;rsquo;t show me the tweets I&amp;rsquo;m interested in, instead it shows me what will make me angry or despairing. Facebook lets me know know which of my friends and family are not-so-secret bigots (I&amp;rsquo;d&amp;rsquo;ve deleted that by now except FB Messenger is the main way I talk to my sister and dad). Instagram seems to exist in order to make me feel bad about myself or to tempt me into buying things I really don&amp;rsquo;t need. None of this is good for my mental health.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I was &lt;a href="https://institute.global/policy/social-media-futures-what-brigading">brigaded on Twitter&lt;/a> earlier this year for a casual, off-hand remark I made to some friends after the Hugo Awards ceremony and the ringleaders harassed me for &lt;em>months&lt;/em> for no reason other that they &lt;em>could&lt;/em>. And because I was not someone that the wider SFF community perceived as important, I was more or less left to deal with it alone. (Those of you who did support me, you have my :purple_heart: forever. The rest of you? :fu: )&lt;/p>
&lt;p>So this is an attempt to get back to basics&amp;ndash;to write a few times a week about how I&amp;rsquo;m feeling (current status: ow my pancreas), about what I&amp;rsquo;m reading, and whatever else I want. And most importantly: to work at becoming a &lt;em>better&lt;/em> writer.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I want to get away from the corporatized and capitalism-focused web and back to what attracted me to the internet in the first place: finding interesting people and reading what they have to say.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m not planning on glossing over any of my health issues, but I&amp;rsquo;m not going to wallow in them or present myself as some sort of heroine fighting a battle with her body: my goal is to make peace with this body, as it&amp;rsquo;s the only one I get to have. And if I have to use assistive devices and medications in order to keep going, then that&amp;rsquo;s what I&amp;rsquo;m going to do. And I&amp;rsquo;m going to talk about it&amp;ndash;there are so few of us who have survived necrotizing pancreatitis writing honestly about what it&amp;rsquo;s like that I feel I owe it to my past self to do so.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But my disability isn&amp;rsquo;t all of who I am: I am also a voracious reader and I make things with yarn. I&amp;rsquo;m also a JavaScript developer and I work for a really neat little company and it&amp;rsquo;s so &lt;em>good&lt;/em>, especially when compared with my prior job, which was actively making my health worse through an abusive manager who knew how to use the corporate bureaucracy to her benefit.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I think most of you reading this have noticed that I&amp;rsquo;m not using any part of my legal name on this site, although it is not difficult to discover. I am asking that this deliberate omission be respected as much as possible. I&amp;rsquo;m respecting your privacy by not using any cookies or other tracking technologies, so please respect mine.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally: welcome, world. I&amp;rsquo;m glad you&amp;rsquo;re here for this journey. Let&amp;rsquo;s have some fun.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>