<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>blood on Peculiar Monster</title><link>https://peculiar.monster/tags/blood/</link><description>Recent content in blood on Peculiar Monster</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>GigaMeow</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 16:04:19 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://peculiar.monster/tags/blood/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>This Meatsuit is Annoying</title><link>https://peculiar.monster/posts/this-meatsuit-is-annoying/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 16:04:19 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://peculiar.monster/posts/this-meatsuit-is-annoying/</guid><description>&lt;p>I am just not feeling the thing this week.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I had a mere 2.5L drained last week&lt;sup id="fnref:1">&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">1&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> and you&amp;rsquo;d think that would have helped and&amp;ndash;nope.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I feel bloated and I basically haven&amp;rsquo;t felt hungry so there&amp;rsquo;s been a lot of forcing myself to eat and then I feel like I overate and it&amp;rsquo;s just not pleasant.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And I&amp;rsquo;m having weird random pain in my gut, but not enough to actually call my doctor or go to the ER about. It&amp;rsquo;s been a year and a half since I was hospitalized and my therapist has reminded me that this streak isn&amp;rsquo;t unbreakable, alas.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve also started a new blood thinner, Xarelto. I&amp;rsquo;d been on Eliquis since 2018 and then my prescription insurance (everyone&amp;rsquo;s favorite, Caremark/CVS) decided to take it off the formulary and require a prior authorization so my doctor just switched me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The funny thing is that because of all the hospitalizations I&amp;rsquo;ve had, I have one heck of a stockpile of medication, so I had 6 months of Eliquis to use up before I started the Xarelto. And I can tell the difference: I&amp;rsquo;d bleed a bit more than I&amp;rsquo;d like when I got a cut or scratch, but the Xarelto? Hooboy. I accidentally scratched my arm the other day and bled all over two shirts before it stopped.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Then I was scratching my leg yesterday and accidentally hit a couple of scabs and actual blood dripping down my leg happened, so I stuck a band-aid on and when I took it off before bed last night, I looked at it and there was quite a bit of blood happening.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>And to continue on the blood theme, I had to get labs done in advance of my seeing my specialist in Center City next week,&lt;sup id="fnref:2">&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref">2&lt;/a>&lt;/sup> and I decided to go to the hospital instead of Labcorp. Which actually worked out well: I told the phlebotamist that I was a hard stick and she proceeded to find the one good vein in my arm and get it on the first try and she wanted to know who&amp;rsquo;d told me I was a hard stick. My answer? &amp;ldquo;Every other phlebotamist in this hospital and all of the ones at LabCorp, too.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve a band-aid on my arm and I&amp;rsquo;m a little scared to take it off, even though it&amp;rsquo;s been nearly 7 hours. I gotta say, though, it was &lt;em>nice&lt;/em> to be able to get in and out of the lab like a normal person. Instead of having every phlebotamist in the place taking a (literal) stab at me.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But. I feel like hot garbage and I&amp;rsquo;ve been taking too many naps and I don&amp;rsquo;t know what to do about it. I&amp;rsquo;ll figure something out, I&amp;rsquo;m sure.&lt;/p>
&lt;section class="footnotes" role="doc-endnotes">
&lt;hr>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li id="fn:1" role="doc-endnote">
&lt;p>This isn&amp;rsquo;t very much, I was regularly getting 6 to 8 liters drained a year and a half ago.&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:1" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li id="fn:2" role="doc-endnote">
&lt;p>He&amp;rsquo;s going to tell me that there&amp;rsquo;s nothing more to be done and to hold the course; why I have to spend an hour and a half in the car and $20 on parking to be told that, I don&amp;rsquo;t know.&amp;#160;&lt;a href="#fnref:2" class="footnote-backref" role="doc-backlink">&amp;#x21a9;&amp;#xfe0e;&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;/section></description></item></channel></rss>